[MUSIC]
［音乐］
Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
Okay, well, welcome to Lecture 8 of
好的，欢迎来到2015年冬季学期
Stanford CS193P winter of 2015.
CS193P 的课程
Today we have two major topics we're gonna talk about,
今天我们会讲到两个主要的话题
one is view controller life cycle which is your view
一个是 View Controller 的生命周期
controller gets born.
也就是 View Controller 从产生
It lives and does a lot of things and
然后完成了一系列的操作
then it dies and so you want to be able to find out about
到 View Controller 死亡，你希望能够知道
all those things that are going on and you can.
这些生命周期中，什么事情正在发生，你能在其中做什么
I'm gonna have a brief demo about that and
这里我会有一个简单的关于生命周期的 Demo
then we're gonna go into auto layout and
接着我们涉及 Auto Layout 的内容
I keep promising we're gonna talk about it, so
我保证我们会在这节课中讲到它
I am gonna finally talk about auto layout.
但是我打算最后再讲 Auto Layout
Of course you all ready know a lot about auto layout and
当然，你已经知道一点点 Auto Layout 的知识了
I'm gonna review that.
我们在今天的课程中会先回顾它们
Then we're gonna talk about an important piece of auto
然后，我们会讲一讲 Auto Layout 中一个比较重要的部分
layout that we haven't talked so far which is size classes,
我们从未涉及到的 Size Classes
and then I'll be doing a humongous couple of
这里，我会做一系列的 Demo
demos on auto lab because, you know, it's the kind of thing
来帮助你理解 Auto Layout，你知道，真正看过的东西
you're going to have to see it to really understand it, but
才是最容易理解的
first, let's talk about view controller life cycle.
但是首先，我们先讲一下 View Controller 的生命周期
When we refer to the view controller life cycle,
当我们谈到 View Controller 的生命周期的时候
we're just talking about a sequence of
我们讲的是，在这个 View Controller 的生命周期中
messages that is sent to your view controller as it
一系列发送至它的消息
progresses through its lifetime.
这些消息伴随着整个的生命周期
Why do we care about this?
我们可能会问，为什么我要关心这个？
Well because you very commonly wanna override these
那是因为，你们通常会在你们的子类中覆写这些
messages that are sent to the view controller in
发送给 View Controller 的消息
your subclass to find out what's going on, because you
来知道，你的应用正在干什么
might need to do things, make certain decisions or
因为你可能希望做一些决定或者其他的操作
whatever at certain points in your view controller life
在你的 View Controller 生命周期的某个特定的时刻
cycle, so let's talk about the cycle and how it goes.
所以，让我们来讲一下 View Controller 的生命周期以及它如何工作的
It starts off with creation.
生命周期由创建一个 View Controller 开始
99% of the time, this is from a storyboard, all right.
99%的情况下，它是从 Storyboard 中创建的
As you know, you create these scenes in the storyboard.
你所知道的，你可以在 Storyboard 中创建这些场景
Those scenes have a view controller class associated
这些场景会关联一个 View Controller 的类
with them and you're just, you're segueing to an MVC,
并且，你 segue 到一个 MVC
even if you create an MVC in code, which I don't even talk
甚至是你通过代码来创建一个 MVC 的
about how to do, maybe we'll talk about it a little later
虽然我目前还没有讲到如何通过代码来创建，不过可能之后会讲到
in the quarter, but could look up in the documentation,
不过你还是可以通过查找文档来获取这些方法
it's quite easy.
挺容易的
Even in that case, you're going to instantiate a view
就在这样的情况下，你将会使用一个标识符（identifier）
controller using identifier in the storyboard, okay, and
在 Storyboard 中去初始化一个 View Controller
that's how you're gonna get the view controller,
那就是你如何得到 View Controller 的
so creation is all most always from the storyboard, and
所以，大多数情况下，是通过 Storyboard 创建 View Controller 的
there is an init that gets called, it's kind of a weird
并且，有一个 init 方法被调用，但是是一个挺奇怪的 init 方法
init, initWithCoder, I'm not gonna talk about it too much,
initWithCoder: ，我不打算花时间讲这个方法
I mentioned it a little bit in the reading assignment,
我会在阅读作业中涉及一点点
number one or number two.
好像是作业 No.1 或者 No.2
I don't remember, so there is an init but we try to stay
我不记得了，所以，这里有一个 init
away from init so if we can, if they're somewhere else, and
但是我们尽可能不去调用 init，有其他的初始化方法
in the view control life cycle there's a lot of
在 View Controller 的生命周期里，你可以看到一大堆
somewhere else's to initialize things besides in init, so
除了 init 之外的其他的初始化方法
I'm not even gonna talk about the init right here.
所以我现在并不打算涉及到 init
Okay, what happens after that initialization though?
好的，初始化之后会发生什么呢？
Well, the first thing is,
第一个发生的事情是
you get prepared if you're being segued to, all right,
如果你被 segue 到这个 View Controller 的话，那么你会准备好（get prepared）
the next thing is your outlets are gonna get set, 'kay.
另外一个发生的事情是，你的 outlets 都被设置好了，明白了吗？
It's just we're gonna wire up all those at sign IV outlets
就是那些我们与 IBOutlet 链接的东西
that you have, and then your view controller's gonna
接下来，你的 View Controller 会显示在屏幕上
appear on screen and then it might disappear and
接着消失在屏幕上
then might reappear and then disappear, okay, and
之后可能又显示在屏幕上，再次消失
its geometry might change because of auto rotation or
而且，它的几何位置（geometry）可能因为自动旋转
something else happens and changes the geometry review,
或者发生一些其他的事情导致了几何位置的改变
so that's happening.
这就是发生的东西
And then in obscure cases,
在一些复杂的情况下
you might have a low memory situation on your device and
你可能会遇到一个设备可用内容低的一个情况
the system might try to get you involved to resolve that,
系统可能尝试让你解决这个问题
and we'll talk about that briefly, all right, so
我们会简单地讲讲这个，好的
that's the cycle.
这就是 View Controller 的生命周期
So what are these methods that are involved in that cycle?
在生命周期中，会有哪些方法涉及到呢？
Well you know about the preparation that's prepared
你知道的，preparedForSegue 做了准备工作
for segue and some other MVC that's what prepares you,
一些其他的 MVC 准备你
and you know about outlet setting, right, just
并且，你知道 outlet 设置
system automatically sets your outlook from your storyboard.
即系统自动从 Storyboard 中设置了你的 outlet
So the next thing that happens is loading,
接下去发生的事情，就是载入（loading）
as your view gets load, well we call that outlet setting,
你的视图被载入。在这之前设置了 outlet
the loading process, and when it's done loading it sends you
接着进入载入的过程，当完成载入的时候
this message viewDidLoad.
它会发送一个 viewDidLoad 的消息
ViewDidLoad is an exceptionally good place to
viewDidLoad 是一个非常好的地方
put stuff to initialize your view, why is it so good?
去放置你初始化你的视图的代码，为什么？
Because you're prepared by whoever's segueing to you, and
那是因为，你，View Controller，已经由 segue 到你的对象准备好了
your outlets are all set, 'kay, so you're in
而且你的 outlet 也被设置完成了
great shape to go do things to initialize your view,
你处于一个初始化你的视图操作的最佳时机
cuz you are all kinda set up and ready to go.
因为你需要的设置已经都设置完了，你已经准备做接下来的操作了
Now, when you override viewDidLoad, it's important to
现在，如果你覆写了 viewDidLoad 方法
call super.viewDidLoad and in fact in
一件很重要的事情就是，别忘了调用 super.viewDidLoad
all these life cycle methods you always wanna call super.
而且在 View Controller 中所有生命周期相关的方法中，你始终希望调用 super 的相应方法
You can either call it at the beginning or at the end,
你可以在方法的开头或者结尾调用 super.viewDidLoad
kind of up to you, doesn't really matter usually but
这个你自己来决定，通常不会有太大的关系
you definitely want to let super have a chance to do it,
但是，你希望 super 有机会去做它的事情
'kay, so don't forget about that.
所以，千万不要忘了
Now one thing that you often wanna do in vewDidLoad is
通常你在 viewDidLoad 里做的一件事情是
update your UI, okay?
更新你的用户界面，明白了吗？
Now you're gonna be updating your UI in the property
之前我们说过，一旦你的模型发生了改变
observers of all your things that change the model, and
你会在模型的属性观察器（property observer）中更新用户界面
you should continue to do that because your view
你应该继续去做这个操作，因为你的 View Controller
control might be on screen all ready loaded,
已经被载入，也显示在屏幕上了
someone changes the model, you gotta update the UI.
有些人改变了模型，你必须更新你的用户界面
But when you're first having your thing created and
但是，当你刚创建了一个 View Controller 的时候
you want to update your UI, it's kind of,
你同样需要更新你的用户界面
you know, your property observer's in your model, and
那是因为，你的在模型中的属性观察器
aren't really updating the UI because your outlets aren't
并不会在 outlet 设置之前去真正更新你的用户界面
set maybe because you're in the prepare for
因为你在 preparedForSegue 的过程中
segue phase right?
对吗？
So a lot of times, you get to viewDidLoad and
所以，很多时候，当 View Controller 被调用 viewDidLoad 的时候
you haven't really been able to update your UI because your
用户界面并没有真正被更新，因为你的
outlets haven't been set, so
outlet 在这之前还没有被设置好
viewDidLoad is a great place to then update your UI.
所以，viewDidLoad 是一个更新用户界面的好时候
So if you factor out updating UI into a separate method like
如果你重构了用户界面的代码并将其分离一些其他的代码
we did in the demo called update UI, but
比如我们在 Demo 中称之为 updateUI 的方法
you can call whatever you want, or
但是，你可以调用任何你想要调用的方法
you can even have a couple different UI updating methods,
或者是，你还可以有一些不同的更新用户界面的方法
calling those in viewDidLoad is very common, 'kay,
在 viewDidLoad 里调用它们是很常见的方法
cuz your view is ready to be updated, however, you have to
需要注意的是，虽然你的视图准备被更新
be careful here because your geometry is not yet set, 'kay?
但是，你的几何位置还没有被设置，好吗？
You only get loaded once,
你只会被载入一次
when you first come out of the storyboard and
也就是从 Storyboard 中出来
you get prepared, your outlets gets set,
准备就绪，outlet 设置完毕
you get viewDidLoad, that's it.
你被调用了 viewDidLoad，仅此一次
That only happens once in the lifetime of a view controller,
一个 View Controller 的生命周期中只会有一次
but your geometry, like what your bounds are,
但是你的几何位置，也就是你的边界
that has not been set yet,
在这个时刻还没有被设置
that's not gonna be set till later in its lifetime, okay?
在这个 View Controller 生命周期的较晚的时候，它才会被设置，明白了吗？
So do not do, I should have put this in red, do not put,
所以，不要，我这里把它标记成了红色
do geometry related things in viewDidLoad, 'kay,
不要在 viewDidLoad 里做与几何位置相关的操作
you can do almost everything else in viewDidLoad, but
除此之外，你可以做几乎其他的任何操作
do not do that, 'kay, and we'll talk about where you do
唯独这个不行，你可能会问什么时候才可以做几何位置相关的操作呢？
do those things in a moment here, all right.
我们稍后会讲到
Next one in the life cycle is viewWillAppear,
下一个在生命周期中被调用的方法是 viewWillAppear
'kay, so that's sent to you right before you're going to
当你的 View Controller 马上要显示在屏幕上的时候
appear on screen.
它会被调用
Now, that could be right after viewDidLoad or
这有可能在 viewDidLoad 之后直接被调用
it could be a long time after viewDidLoad.
或者也有可能在 viewDidLoad 之后，过一会儿才被调用
It depends on what's going on in your UI,
这个依赖于你用户界面上做的操作
okay, and viewWillAppear gets an argument, which is
好的，viewWillAppear 会有一个参数
whether it's an animated appearance or not, 'kay?
这个参数表示这个 View Controller 的出现是否有动画效果的
Usually you don't care about that.
通常你不需要关心这个参数
And when would your appearance be animated?
什么时候需要你的 View Controller 的出现带有动画效果呢？
Well you're in a navigation controller and
当你在一个 Navigation Controller 里
someone presses to segue you on screen,
什么东西出发了 segue 到你的 View Controller 的时候
you'll slide in, that's the animation, okay?
那么你会通过滑入的方式显示出来，这就是动画效果，明白了吗？
So, viewWillAppear,
好的，viewWillAppear
this could happen all the time, this could happen
这可以在你的 View Controller 的整个生命周期里多次被调用
repeatedly in the lifetime of your view controller,
cuz your view controller can come on screen or go off.
因为你的 View Controller 能显示在屏幕上，也能从屏幕上消失
Let's think of an example, split view,
让我们设想一个情况，Split View
the master of a split view.
Split View 的 Master
When you first bring up your iPad user interface,
当你第一次打开 iPad 的用户界面时候
it's in portrait, you don't see the master,
它是在竖屏模式（portrait）的，你不会看到 Master
you have to kind of slide it out to see the master,
你必须通过滑动来显示 Master
you only see the detail, right, so it's not visible.
这种情况下，你只能看到 Detail，Master 是不可见的
You rotate to landscape, now the master becomes visible, so
但是，当你旋转你的设备到横屏模式（landscape）的时候，那么 Master 就变的可见了
you're gonna get viewWillAppear.
这时候 viewWillAppear 会被调用
You rotate back to portrait, it's off screen.
当你又旋转回竖屏模式的时候，Master 从屏幕上消失了
You rotate back to landscape, it's gonna appear again,
然后你又旋转到横屏模式，又显示了
it's gonna send you viewWillAppear again.
viewWillAppear 又会被调用
So you're gonna get viewWillAppear every time it
所以，每一次 Master 显示在屏幕上的时候
appears on screen,
viewWillAppear 都会被调用
'kay, now what would you do when a viewWillAppear?
那么在 viewWillAppear 中，你能够做些什么呢？
A lot of times maybe, if you have to do something very
可能通常的情况下，如果你需要做一些费时间的事情
expensive, like let's say you have to go out to the network
比如你到网络上去获取什么东西
to get something, an image or something like that,
一个图片或者其他的
you might not want to do that in viewDidLoad because maybe
你不想让这些代码在 viewDidLoad 中允许因为
the user never turns view to landscape and never looks at
用户可能从来不会将屏幕横过来
your master, maybe you've got an app where the details all
从来不会看你的 Master，用户只关心 Detail 中的内容
are that matters and people rarely pull out the master.
很少用户会拉出 Master 来看
Well, you wouldn't wanna do
那么，你不想每一次都调用这些花时间的代码
that expensive thing until the master actually appeared.
只有当 Master 真正要显示的时候你才希望调用这些代码
Now, you're gonna wanna do that expensive thing in
而且， 通常你希望能够将这些花时间的代码
another thread, we'll talk about it on
跑在另外一个线程中，这个我们周三会提到
Wednesday to keep the main thread active.
如何保持主线程不被阻塞
And, of course, when that master appeared, if
而且，如果当 Master 显示的时候
you're waiting for something on the network there's gonna
如果你在等待网络上的数据返回
be a blank space or something that we'll fill in later,
Master 会是一片空白，或者是一些我们稍后会填充的东西
maybe you put a spinning wheel, things like that, but
或许你会放置一个 Loading 的滚轮，或者其他的东西
viewWillAppear since you know you're actually gonna get on
viewWillAppear 已经知道，你要放置在屏幕上的东西可能要花一点点时间
screen is a place we might kick off something that's
你目前放置的是一个替代物，之后会被替换
a little bit expensive, also your geometry is set here.
同时你的几何位置也被设置好了
Okay, by the time you get view will appear your bounds,
所以，当 viewWillAppear 被调用的时候
your view's bounds, you're a view controller right, so
你视图的边界，还记得你是一个 View Controller 吧？
your view's bound, view.bound is set, so
你视图的边界，view.bound 已经设置好了
you can do geometry stuff here.
那么你可以在这里做一些几何位置相关的代码
It's legal and you might want to, 'kay, but
这是完全没有问题的，也正是你希望的
I'm gonna show you another place you can do that as well
但是，在后面几个 Slide 中，我想给你们展示一个另外的地方
on the next couple slides.
同样你可以做一些几何位置相关的代码
There's also a viewDidAppear in addition to viewWillAppear,
除了 viewWillAppear 之外，还有一个 viewDidAppear
'kay, so
好的
viewDidAppear gets sent to you after you are now on screen.
当你已经显示在屏幕上之后，viewDidAppear 被调用
You are visible now, 'kay, pretty straightforward, and
此时你是可见的，明白了吗？很明显易懂
similarly there's viewWillDisappear, so
同样的，与这两个方法相对，有 viewWillDeisappear
you're just about to be taken off screen.
你正要从屏幕上消失的时候被调用
Again, you're the split view master in landscape,
我们接着上面举的例子，你是横屏模式中 Split View 中的 Master
the person rotates the portrait, you're gonna
如果用户旋转到了竖屏模式，那么
get viewWillDisappear cuz you're going to disappear,
你的 View Controller 会被调用 viewWillDisappear 方法，因为 Master 视图从屏幕上消失了
it's just going to show only the detail, 'kay?
随后，屏幕上只会显示 Detail，明白了吗？
Here you might clean up some stuff, you might get rid of
这里你可以做一些清理的操作，你可能会
some resources that are expensive, like a big image or
清除一些占用资源的对象，类似于一副大图
something that you can reconstitute fairly quickly,
或者其他你能够快速
maybe from disk or something.
从磁盘中恢复的东西
That's the kind of thing you'll do in
这就是你要在 viewWillDisappear 中做的，当然
viewWillDisappear, and of course, there's a did version
同样的，viewWillDisappear 也有一个 did 版本
of this too, viewDidDisappear, 'kay, so that will disappear,
viewDidDisappear，明白了吗？
will appear and will disappear in their dids, okay?
willAppear 和 willDisappear 的 did 形态
Now let's talk about geometry.
接下来，让我们讲一下几何位置
So when your geometry changes, when your bounds change,
当你几何位置有所变化时，你的边界同样发生了变化
the system knows that your bounds changed, and
系统知道你的边界改变了，而且
it knows that you probably have to re-layout your user
他知道，你大概需要重新布局你的用户界面
interface, okay?
Now 99% of the time, that's gonna happen by magic because
所以，99%的情况下，重新布局是自动完成的
you've set up your auto layout properly, right, so
因为你已经设置好了 Auto Layout 属性
you don't even have to do anything, but if for
所以你甚至不需要去做其他的事情
some reason you wanted to do something,
但是鉴于某些原因，你可能想在这个过程中做什么的话
you can override one of these two methods,
你可以覆写两个方法中的一个
viewWillLayoutSubviews and viewDidLayoutSubviews,
viewWillLayoutSubviews 和 viewDidLayoutSubviews
so the system calls viewWillLayoutSubviews anytime
然后系统会在它认为合适的时候去调用 viewWillLayoutSubviews
it wants to,
make sure that your views are properly laid out.
确保你的视图被正确布局
Now, when it calls, this is not viewsBoundsDidChange,
现在，当它调用的时候，注意这个方法名字不是 viewsBoundsDidChange
that's not the name of this method,
这不是这个方法的名字
okay, it's a viewWillLayoutSubviews, so
这个方法名字是 viewWillLayoutSubviews
your subviews can get laid out for lots of different reasons,
你的子视图会因为多种原因被重新布局
maybe one of your subviews changes in a way that causes
可能你视图中的一个发生了改变
it to change shape and has to be relaid out, et cetera.
比如它的形状发生了改变，整个视图需要重新布局，或者其他类似的情况
So, viewWillLayoutSubviews is sent to
所以，当你的视图层次或者你的顶层视图的边界发生改变的时候
you when someone inside your
你会收到 viewWillLayoutSubviews 的消息
view hierarchy or your top level bounds change in a way
where the system needs you to layout your subviews, okay?
因为系统需要你去重新布局你的子视图，明白了吗？
Now, you can make this happen by calling, just like you
你可以通过通过调用来实现这个
have set needs display you can say set needs layout.
就像你设置 setNeedsDisplay 那样，setNeedsLayout
You say set needs layout, then the next pass around the event
当你调用了 setNeedsLayout 之后，在下一轮的 Event Loop 中
loop, the system will re-layout your subviews, 'kay.
系统会重新布局你的子视图，明白了吗？
Now this can be called, quite often this viewWill and
viewWillLayoutSubviews 和 viewDidLayoutSubviews
DidLayoutSubviews because changes are being made all
经常被调用，因为无时无刻都会发生变化
the time and the system doesn't
系统并不是始终都知道
always quite know whether that affected your subview, so
是否某个操作影响了你的子视图
it might ask you to just lay them out again, okay?
所以它可能会让你重新来对子视图布局，明白了吗？
So don't be surprised when you get viewWillLayoutSubviews two
所以，当你的边界改动了一次
or three times when the bounds only changed once, let's say,
但是你的 viewWillLayoutSubviews 方法被调用了两次或者三次的时候，不要觉得惊讶
'kay, and you have to,
而且，你需要
if you're gonna do something in these two methods,
如果你在这两个方法中做了什么的话
you're gonna have to do the right thing,
你必须做的对
even if like your bounds don't actually change.
甚至是，你的边界并没有真正改变的情况下
This whole process of laying out your subviews,
整个布局你子视图的过程
the idea is to make sure that your subviews
唯一的想法就是，确保你的子视图是
are properly laid out.
正确被布局的
Now again, most of that's happening with auto layout,
在一次重申，大多数布局都可以通过 Auto Layout 来做到
and the auto layout happens between these two methods, so
Auto Layout 在这两个方法之间起作用
you get view a layout subviews, you do whatever you
首先是 viewWillLayoutSubviews，接着做任何你想做的
wanna do, then auto layout happens, then you get
然后，Auto Layout 起作用
viewDidLayoutSubviews, 'kay, so your subviews might have
接下来，viewDidLayoutSubviews，好的
moved around between the two calls of these, make sense?
你的子视图可能在这两个方法调用之中被移动了，明白了吗？
Any questions about that?
有什么问题吗？
So, yeah, these things might be called quite a lot and
好的，这些方法可能会经常被调用到
we'll see that in the demo that they might get called,
我们可以在 Demo 中看到，这些方法可能被调用
and called, and called.
调用、调用
Autorotation, really you wanna think of
Autorotation，真正要考虑的是
autorotation primarily as just your bounds changed, so
你的边界的改变
autorotation is really a non-event.
所以 Autorotation 其实不是一个事件
As we have seen in all of our apps we have been writing so
目前为止，我们在我们的 App 中编写的代码
far, we don't even think about autorotation,
我们根本没有考虑过 Autorotation
it just happens our bounds change, auto layout works and
它自动发生，我们的边界改变，Auto Layout 工作
the world is good.
一切都很正常
And that's the way you should think of it 99% of the time,
那就是你99%的情况下会考虑的
but if for some reason,
但是在某些原因之下
you care about the actual case where rotation is happening,
你需要关心一下，怎么样的旋转正在发生？
in other words, your device got turned and
换言之，你的设备旋转了
so the bounds got to be wider than tall and when they used
边界是变宽了还是变窄了
to be taller than wide, then you can participate.
然后你可以参与这个过程，做一些事情
By the way, first line there says you can go to
顺便一提，这里的第一行说了，你可以
your project settings and
到你的项目设置（Project Settings）中
prevent certain autorotation from happening,
取消特定的 Autorotation
and the default by the way is that portrait upside down
默认取消的是，颠倒的竖屏模式
is prevented.
That's why you noticed your app,
这就是你在我们的 App 中看到的
you go in the simulator and you rotate it to landscape and
当你在模拟器中，你旋转到了横屏模式
then you rotate it again to upside down and
然后你再进行一次旋转，到了颠倒的竖屏模式
it doesn't autorotate,
我们的 App 并没有自动旋转
that's because in your private setting you said, oh,
这是因为在你的项目设置中，你说
portrait upside down is not a supported orientation.
“不支持颠倒的竖屏模式”
So when you go to portrait upside down,
所以，当你的 App 处于颠倒的竖屏模式中
it just does not autorotate, and you can flip those four
Autorotation 将不起作用，当然你可以
switches for the landscapes and portraits any way you
随意开关竖屏模式和横屏模式的四种模式
want, okay, it depends on your UI and what makes sense.
这一切都取决于你的用户界面
Some UIs make no sense in landscape, some only make
一些用户界面不需要横屏模式
sense in landscape, there might be a game or
一些用户界面只需要横屏模式，比如说游戏
something that just doesn't make sense in portrait, 'kay?
或者其他不适用于竖屏模式的应用，明白了吗？
So, but if you want to participate in the
所以，如果你想在 Autorotation 中插一手的话
autorotation, 'kay, like you want to do some animation of
比如你想要定制你自己的动画效果
your own, because you notice that the rotation is animated,
你注意到了旋转中的动画效果了吗？
right it goes from portrait to landscape, it kinda moves the
对，比如从竖屏模式切换到横屏模式
views around, it's hard to see cause it's happening so fast,
它移动了视图，但这个效果很难看清，因为速度实在是太快了
but it is animating it, and you can actually participate
但是，肯定是有动画的，你可以参与其中
that by this method viewWillTransitionToSize,
通过 viewWillTransitionToSize 这个方法
which is part of the life cycle.
同样也是 View Controller 生命周期的一部分
And this transition coordinator you get,
而且你得到的变换坐标系
now I'm not gonna talk about how to implement this,
现在我不打算说，如何去实现它
I haven't even talked about animation,
因为我目前还没有谈到动画这部分
we're not gonna talk about that for a couple of weeks,
所以在最近的几周里，我们都不会讲到它
but there is a method in that coordinator, for example,
但是在那个 coordinator中有一个方法，比如说
called animate alongside, and you can specify what kinda
叫做 animate alongside，并且你可以指定什么样的
animations you want to animate alongside the rotation.
动画你想要 animate alongside回转
So I'm just telling you this now because it's part of
the view controller life cycle and
you should just know in your head that it exists.
Okay, it's a little bit of a complicated thing to use,
because when you rotate and you change bounds, really it's
container views that are most concerned with that, like
a split view, it needs to now put both things on screen and
put a line and when you switch the other way.
It's really about container views, a little less than
about leaf view controllers, but leaf view controller might
wanna know what's going on, all right, and
then low memory, you get this didReceiveMemoryWarning.
Here you wanna throw away anything in
the heap that's easy to reconstitute.
The way you throw things out of the heap, by the way,
is you just set all pointers that you have to them to nil,
okay, if you're not pointing to something,
then it won't stay in the heap, it gets thrown out.
That does not include weak pointers.
If you have a weak pointer to something,
it still gets thrown out, 'kay?
If the only pointer in the world to an image in the heap
is a weak pointer, it's gonna get pitched, and
that weak pointer's gonna get set to nil,
'kay, as we talked about when we talked about delegation,
'kay, that's the definition of a weak pointer, okay?
So, in low memory situations, you know, try to clean up.
You'll all most never get this,
you may never, ever get this.
If your app is very highly image intensive,
maybe it's an image processing app and
you've got a lot of images in there, then it's possible,
I suppose, but it's extremely unlikely,
'kay, there's a lot of memory in these devices.
Okay, now I'm gonna go back to awakeFromNib, which is not
really part of the view controller life cycle,
but a view controller,
just like any other NS object subclass that comes out of
a storyboard, will get awakeFromNib.
And there are some students, as a class in the past,
that have kind of abused awakeFromNib and they just
start trying to put everything in their initialization into
awakeFromNib instead of putting it into viewDidLoad or
viewWillAppear, or viewWillLayoutSubviews,
depending on what kind of thing it is.
And I'm just warning you here, don't abuse awakeFromNib, but
there are some cases where awakeFromNib is necessary.
For example, if you want to set yourself as the delegate
of the split view controller you're in, awayFromNib is
a good place to do that, because then it happens really
early and you'll start getting those delegate methods from
split view as you go through the rest of your life cycle.
Okay?
So there are some times when awakeFromNib is good.
All right, so here's the summary of the life cycle.
You get instantiated, usually from the storyboard.
You're gonna get awakeFromNib.
Segue prep is gonna happen.
Your outlets are gonna get set by the system.
ViewDidLoad is gonna get called.
View will appear and disappear.
It's gonna happen as your controller goes on and
off screen.
And as your view controller's geometry changes or
the subviews change in a way that needs to be re-laid out,
you're gonna get WillLayoutSubviews,
then autolayout, then DidLayoutSubviews.
So that could happen many times.
And if you get low on memory,
you could have this memory warning, okay?
So that's the View Controller Lifecycle.
There is actually one other one in here.
It'll tell you when your size class changes.
But I haven't talked about size class yet, so
I didn't put that in this list.
But there's one more, and
there will transition to traits or something like that.
All right, so I'm gonna do a quick demo here, super fast.
Let me get something to drink here, okay?
So I'm gonna do a quick demo.
And all I did is I took Psychologist from last time,
and I just put a bunch of printlns in all
these View Controler Lifecycle methods, okay?
So that it would just print out where it is in
Lifecycle all the time.
So, let's go do that.
Let's go run that.
It is here in Developer, Psychologist Lecture 8.
Here we go.
So you can see that in viewWillAppear() I
put a little log for that, disappear, all these.
So I'm just making it basically
logging all the things that are happening, okay.
So lets go, I'm gonna run this on iPad.
It's a little easier to make things happen here.
All right, so here's our Psychologist.
I haven't changed anything about the app.
I'm gonna make the console really big so
that we can see what's going on here.
All right, so notice we came up.
The detail is the only thing,
the detail is Happiness View Controller.
It's the only thing visible.
So what happened here?
The Psychologist got pulled out of the storyboard.
The Happiness got pulled out of the storyboard.
This zero is which instance of it.
Cuz we're gonna have multiple instances, eventually.
Then Happiness got awakeFromNib.
Then Psychologist got awakeFromNib.
The order of awakeFromNib is completely not determinable,
so you should not depend on it.
Then the master got viewDidLoad.
Even though the master never appears on screen,
it still had its outlet set, and
got viewDidLoad sent to it.
Then interestingly, the master was asked to lay itself out,
to lay its Subviews out.
Okay again, it hasn't appeared.
It hasn't even gotten viewWillAppear,
because it's not gonna appear.
But its Subviews wanna get laid out.
And why is this happen?
Well, you know, the system might be
preparing to animate it onscreen or something.
You just want to make sure.
This is not doing any drawing.
This is just making sure
the Subviews are properly laid out.
It happens twice here, maybe a before and after animation.
Who knows what's going on here,
it doesn't really matter.
The size didn't actually change.
Okay, the bound size didn't actually change, so
this second one probably did almost nothing here.
Then the detail, Happiness, it gets a videwDidLoad and then
it gets a viewWillAppear, cuz it's gonna appear onscreen.
The animated is false because it doesn't animate on screen.
It was the initial thing that shows up in screen, so
boom, it just pops up there.
It gets laid out and then it gets viewDidAppear.
And here it is, okay?
Everyone understand that?
Now I'm going to rotate to landscape, and
that's gonna cause the master to appear.
So watch this.
So we do rotate,
all these dash, that's what happened since I rotated here.
And you can see Psychologist and Happiness both got
informed that this transition to size is going to happen.
So they could have
participated in the animation if they want, and you're gonna
see the animation happen in a little bit down the road here.
The master got another chance to lay its Subviews out in
a little different size.
Because this size, it's only 768 high instead of
the full 1024, and it's a little wider too.
So it got laid out, then it got viewWillAppear.
So this guy was told it would appear, okay?
And this guy didn't get any viewWillAppear because it's
already there.
So it's not appearing, it was already there before.
So it gets viewWillAppear.
Now the detail gets chance to lay its Subviews out here at
a new size.
Because it used to be the whole screen,
now it's just this part right here, so it got a new layout.
And then the master was asked to layout its Subviews again.
So you see how I'm saying this gets called a lot.
So you just need to
make sure that if you're doing anything in these two methods,
that it's okay to be doing it over and over.
Here's where the actually animation happens.
And you can see that both the Psychologist and the Happiness
have been invited to animate alongside if they wanted to.
Then the master is asked to layout one more time,
same size.
That's the third time its been asked to do that.
And then the master gets viewDataAppear, okay?
Now the last thing I'm gonna do is click one of these,
which is gonna cause a segue which is gonna cause this to
be replaced.
So let's do that.
So we'll try the dancing tree here.
Okay?
So what happened here?
A new Happiness.
Happiness 1 got instantiated here, okay?
We have Happiness 0 up here and Happiness 1.
It got prepared with Happiness of a hundred.
Okay?
Then layout Subviews of the master again.
Then the Happiness 0 got viewWillDisappear.
Happiness 0, that old Happiness of
course getting pulled out and
replaced by the new one, so it got viewWillDisappear.
Then the master got laid out again, and
then viewDidLoad happened on Happiness 1,
the new happiness that's appearing.
Then it got viewWillAppear cuz it's going to appear.
Then it got a chance to be laid out.
The old Happiness disappeared.
The new Happiness appeared and then the old
Happiness got deinitialized, thrown out of the heap.
Because like I said, once you segue away from it,
boom, it's gone.
Okay? So that's all I
wanted to cover there.
Everybody cool with that?
Any questions about that View Controller Lifecycle?
It's pretty straightforward, but you can already probably
imagine in your head some things that you were
doing in your code that's like oh, I wish I had viewDidLoad.
That really could have
initialized some stuff there a little simpler.
All right, so let's go back to our slides.
All right, so you've seen a lot of Autolayout already in
this class, so
I'm gonna review briefly the things you should know.
One is you know about using the dashed lines.
Using the blue dashed lines is helping the interface builder.
By the way, when I refer to interface builder,
that means Xcode, the storyboard part of Xcode.
We call that interface builder for historical reasons.
So, when you're in the storyboard of Xcode,
the dashed lines are kind of telling Xcode what you want,
what you intend.
As best that you can, okay?
Then you know about Ctrl-dragging between views to
create relationships, right?
Like spacing, and hook this to the left edge, and
stuff like that.
You know about those in the lower right corner,
the "Pin" and "Arranged" popovers down there that let
you do things like set all the things to equal widths, or
create spacing between all of them, or
line up their left edges, okay?
You know about using Reset to Suggested Constraints.
If you use the blue lines,
sometimes you'll do Reset to Suggested Constraints, and
it will actually figure out what you want.
I'd say only 50 percent of the time,
but it's worth a try sometimes.
The Document Outline,
you know that on the left in the document outline,
all your constraints are listed there.
Okay. And also that's where,
if you've got problems, you can click on the little red or
yellow button in the upper right-hand corner of
the Document Outline and it'll tell you.
It might even suggest some ways to fix things, possibly.
And certainly will tell you if anything's misplaced.
And you know from there, you can also fix your misplaced
views by clicking on the little triangles in there.
You know about the size inspector.
If you inspect a view in your storyboard and
you look at the size inspector,
you'll see all the constraints listed there.
In there, all the constraints are shown with their details.
Okay?
What the constants are, all that stuff, is listed there.
And of course you can edit the constraints there.
You can also, you know that you can click on a constraint.
And bring up the attributes inspector.
And now you can inspect the constraint directly, okay?
It will be the thing that's selected so the attributes
inspector will let you set its attributes, okay?
So you know a lot here about autolayout.
And that is basically what autolayout is.
It's those things.
Okay, now again, as I've said many times,
mastering autolayout requires experience.
You gotta know how to use all these tools,
to greatest effect, okay.
You gotta familiarize yourself with what things can I
align to things, what things can I pin to here and there,
what things can I set as my constants that make sense.
You gotta learn all that by doing, okay.
I could spend many days going through every possible one.
Autolayout can be done in code.
There are objects, classes,
in iOS that represent what's going on in autolayout.
And in the demo I'm gonna actually show you an example
of doing that so you can get an idea of what it looks like.
But we rarely do that.
If we can do it in the storyboard, we do it there.
We only revert to doing it in code when it's like,
we just can't express that somehow in the storyboard,
which is extremely rare.
But I'll show you a case where that's true, but all right.
So what about rotation?
As I said, when you have rotation,
you're just going to rely on your autolayout to do that.
But occasionally when you rotate, things have changed so
drastically in terms of the shape that autolayout just
can't do it.
It can't move a view where you want.
So what's an example of that?
所以有什么这方面的例子呢？
Lets consider our calculator.
让我回忆一下我们的计算器
Okay lets say we had 20 buttons in our calculator.
好的，我们的计算器有20个按键
Okay.
好的
Now in landscape,
现在横屏
I might want them to be five buttons across and four down.
那么我希望它应该有五列四行
But when I switch to portrait,
但是当我想转换成竖屏
now I might want four across and five down.
现在我希望它是四列五行
Okay, there's no
没有办法
way you're gonna write autolayout to do that.
使用自动布局去实现这个效果
Autolayout cannot make such a huge change like doing that.
自动布局不能做如此巨大的变动
Okay, so how do we deal with that?
所以我们该怎么解决呢？
We still wanna do that, so how do we do it?
我们仍然想要做到这个效果，那我们要怎么做呢?
It's not just in the case of rotation where this is
这也并不是只在旋转情况下
happening to.
发生
It also happens, for example, in a split view.
它也同样发生在, 比如说分屏的时候
When you have the master in the spilt view on the left,
当你左侧屏幕的主干
it kind of is tall and thin, just like it was on an iPhone.
它高高瘦瘦的, 就像它在 iPhone 一样
Even though it was on an iPad, it's kind of in a shape,
但是它其实是在 iPad 上，就像在一块形状里面
a space that's shaped more like an iPhone, right?
一个就像 iPhone 的形状，懂吗？
Lots of vertical space, but not much horizontal space.
有很多垂直空间，但是只有很少的水平空间
So it's not just rotation where we
也并不是只有在旋转
care about this size business, the relative size of things.
我们所在意的尺寸，相对大小事物
So the solution to this is called size classes, and so
因此这解决方式叫作尺寸等级，并且
your view controller always exists in
的视图控制器一直存在
a size class environment.
这个尺寸等级的环境里
For width and height.
对于所有的宽度高度来说
And currently the size class can either be compact
并且当前的尺寸等级可以是紧凑的
or regular.
或者是普通的
Regular just means it's not compact.
普通意味着就不紧凑
Okay, and so lets try and
好的, 让我们试一下
understand what when you're in these different situations.
理解当你在这些不同的情景之下的反应
So for example the iPhone 6+ is an interesting device.
比如 iPhone6+是一个有意思的设备
In portrait it's width is compact.
在竖屏下它的宽是紧凑的
It's height is regular.
它的高是普通的
Okay so that's if you
因此如果你
had like a full screen view controller on an iPhone 6+.
在 iPhone 6+ 上满屏操作
When you go to landscape on the 6+ now it's compact in
当你6+横屏时现在高
height and regular in width.
紧凑, 宽普通
That make sense?
要怎么做呢？
All right, it makes perfect sense in that one.
当然, 要做一个完美的感受
But the iPhone is kind of an interesting one,
但是 iPhone 是一个有意思的设备
other iPhones besides the iPhone 6+,
其他 iPhone 除 iPhone 6+ 之外的
in portrait it is compact in width and regular in height,
竖屏时宽紧凑高普通
just like an iPhone 6+, but in landscaped,
就像是 iPhone 6+, 但是在横屏的时候
it is considered compact in width and compact in height.
它应该被考虑成宽紧凑高也是紧凑
And that might seem non-intuitive,.
它不是凭直觉的
But it just turns out that a non iPhone 6+, the width of
但是事实证明非 iPhone 6+，这个宽
it is just not quite enough to say this is a regular width.
它不充分作为普通宽
Most UIs just will look better if you
大部分 UI 只是看起来友好如果你
consider it compact, okay?
只是考虑它的紧凑性，了解吗？
Now the iPad is always regular in both directions.
现在 iPad 一直作为全方向上的普通处理
Portrait or landscape, it's always so
竖屏或者横屏，它一直都是
big that it's just regular in both directions.
大并且全方向普通
There's no compact on the iPad.
iPad 上面没有紧凑
But again a particular view controller on
但是再次声明一个特别的视图控制器
an iPad like the master of
在 iPad 上面主要
a split view side by side that's going to be compact.
分屏并列紧凑的
Regular height, compact width.
普通的高, 紧凑的宽
All right, this whole thing is extensible it's not kinda all
当然, 整个事物都是可扩展的, 它没有
frozen in stone.
固定住
You if you have a view controller you can find out
你如果你有一个视图控制器你可以发现
your size class by using this property called trait
你尺寸等级，它是通过使用的属性即特征
collection.
集合
And inside traitCollection,
并且在特征集合里
it's gonna return the horizontal size class and
它将返回水平尺寸等级和
the vertical size class,
竖直尺寸等级
and that's just an enum that's either .Compact or
并且这只是枚举的两种。紧凑
.Regular, okay?
或者普通，了解？
Now, you probably almost never need to do this because you're
现在你很可能几乎从不需要这些因为你将
gonna edit this in your storyboard, 'kay?
在 storyboard 里编辑，了解吗？
You're going to set up your storyboard to deal with
你将设置你的 storyboard 去处理
size classes.
尺寸等级
And then your code, it's just all gonna work.
然后你的代码，它将正常工作
Okay as long as you got your
直到你的自动布局
rest of your auto layout going.
不起作用的时候
So how does that work?
要怎么让它工作？
All right so here's the size classes right horizontal and
当然这里有尺寸等级正确的水平和
vertical, compact and regular.
垂直，紧凑和普通
See these four boxes right,
看四个盒子
that's every possible combination.
这每一个都可能是混合的
Okay and so for my calculator for example here's what
对于我们的计算器比如这里
my UI might look like in those situations.
我们的 UI 可能看起来在这些情况下
Okay you see here that I've gone five across and four
你所看到的这里有五列四行
down when I have a compact height and regular width.
当它高紧凑宽普通
But I basically anytime I have a regular width I'm gonna
但是我基本定期有一个普通的宽我将
go what did I do, every time I actually every time I have.
做我该做的，每一次的确每一次都如此
A regular height, I go five high.
一个普通的高度，我设置5列
Okay so lower right is regular height, it's five high.
当然右下角是个普通高，它是五列
Lower left is regular height is five high.
左下角普通高也是五列
The top two are compact height,
最上两个是紧凑高
I've gone to four high five wide.
我将设置四列五行
Okay.
当然
So it'd be kinda a pain though if I had to do all four of
它有些问题以至于我只能设置四个
these for every user interface I built.
这些每一个我建立的用户界面
So we actually have another size class called any.
因此我们的确有其他的尺寸等级
And if you throw any into the mix,
并且如果你抛弃这些混乱的
now I can do this exactly the way I just said which is.
现在我可以确定这个我所说的这个方式
Any, first of all I'm gonna have an any any,
当然，起先我需要这个 any any
which is the middle, and that's gonna be my base UI.
这个在中间，这些作为我的基本用户界面
So, if I don't specify any particular size class, it's
因此，如果我指定一些特殊的尺寸等级
gonna look like that, which is four across and five down.
它就像是这个四列五行
But in the case where it's vertically compact.
但是在这个垂直紧凑的条件下
I'm going to go to five across and only four high.
我将它设置为五列可是只有四列
And I don't care what the width is so
并且我不关心它的宽度
that's why it's any.
为什么它是 any
So now I only have to do two user interfaces.
现在我只想做好这两个用户界面
My main user interface, the any any and one other one
我的主要的用户界面，any any 和这个和另外一个
which is I'm in a compact vertical situation so
在这个紧凑的垂直条件下
I want to go four high.
我想有四列
Okay so this makes it a little easier now I only have to do
这有点简单现在我就想
things and
这个和
still covers all the same bases as the previous slide.
仍然覆盖的所有的正如之前幻灯片相同的基本框架
And incredibly, Interface Builder will have a graph that
难以置信的是，界面建立者将有一个图形
looks almost exactly like this slide that lets you pick
看起来就像幻灯片所说的你所选的
between these various boxes, and you can design your
这些不同盒子之间的，你可以设计你
user interface in any of these boxes.
用户界面
Okay? And it will
好？然后它将
just magically work.
只是神奇地运作
So let's take a look at a demo here.
因此让它看起来就像这里的例子
I actually have a couple of demos.
我的确有一对演示
The one is called ShowSizeClass,
这个个叫做 ShowSizeClass
it's just an app that I wrote that shows the size
这个应用，我是为了展示尺寸
class of whatever device you're on at the time.
等级不管你现在处于何种设备之下
Okay?
可否？
And we're gonna take a look at the code for that.
我们将看一下这个代码
And then I'm gonna do an app from scratch.
然后我先用 scratch 做这个应用
Which is called Autolayout.
这个被称为自动布局
That's the name of my app.
这是应用的名称
Add it's just gonna have some
添加这个将有一些
very interesting autolayout things including
非常有趣的自动布局的包括
the size class problem that we're gonna have to solve.
尺寸等级等这些我们会解决的问题
Okay so it's kind of kitchen sink of that.
这就像是厨房的污水槽
All right let's go and
接下来
look at this app I wrote called ShowSizeClass.
看这个我写的被称为 ShowSizeClass 的应用
So here's ShowSizeClass, and
在这个 ShowSizeClass 应用里
I'm just going to run this on some various devices.
我将运行在这些设备上
Let's run this on an iPhone 6 Plus for example.
例如让我们先运行在 iPhone 6+ 上
Here's an iPhone 6 Plus.
这是 iPhone 6 +
How do I make this small?
怎么把它变小？
I guess I can't.
我猜我不能
This is as small as I can make it.
这是我所能做到的最小的
You see how iPhone 6 Plus in portrait here
你看到 iPhone 6 + 在这里怎样竖屏
is horizontally compact.
水平紧凑的
And it's regular vertically.
并且竖直普通的
That's what the green means.
这是绿颜色的意思
Okay?
下一步？
If I rotate it, it's regular horizontally and
如果我旋转它，它是水平整齐
compact vertically.
竖直紧凑的
Everybody cool with that?
大家是不是觉得它相当酷炫？
All right. Now,
当然，现在
let's look on the iPhone 6.
让我们再看回 iPhone 6
All right, iPhone 6 again,
当然，再一次 iPhone 6
regular vertically, compact width.
垂直普通，水平紧凑
But if we rotate, it's compact in both directions.
但是如果我们旋转，它将全方向紧凑了
Okay, let's go to like iPhone 4s or something like that.
下一步，让我们看 iPhone 4s 或者其他设备
Okay, so here's 4S.
这是 4s
It's also, even though it's kind of short,
也是，虽然它看起来有点短
it's still considered regular vertically.
它仍然是垂直普通的
And compact this way,
这个紧凑的方式
and compact in both directions just like an iPhone 6.
全方向紧凑就像是 iPhone 6
Okay?
下一步？
And lastly, let's take a quick look at iPad2, or any iPad.
最后，让我们看一下 iPad2，或者其他 iPad
I do iPad too because it fits on this screen.
我选 iPad 是因为它有合适的屏幕
All the rest of them are too high of resolution again.
其余的又太高了
All right, look, see.
看这里
It's regular this way and regular both ways,
这个方式是普通的并且所有方式都是普通的
this way, okay.
这个方向，当然
So let's look at the app that I wrote to do that.
因此让我们看我写的这个应用
I keep going back here to iPhone 6.
我将回到 iPhone 6
Okay, let's look at the app that I wrote.
让我们看一下这个我写的应用
Here it is, ShowSizeClass.
这里，ShowSizeClass
It has a storyboard here.
这是一个 storyboard
Here's its storyboard.
这是 storyboard
Let's see if we can find anything in the storyboard.
让我们看看如果我们可以发现 storyboard 的其他东西
There it is, okay.
这里，好的
Hm, nteresting.
恩，有趣
This storyboard, there's no arrows.
这个 storyboard，没有箭头
There's the dot in the middle, but
这里中间有个小黑点，但是
where the heck did those arrows?
没有箭头？
Oh, I must draw them in my code.
哦，我必须把他们画到我的代码里
Let's look at the View control.
让我们看这个视图控制器
Oh, my View control had no code.
哦，我的视图控制器没有代码
This app has no code.
这个应用没有代码
How is it possible that it drew those arrows, okay?
我怎样画出这些箭头呢？
Well, the answer is that those arrows are only drawn for
这些箭头是画来解决
the SizeClass in question.
这个 SIzeClass 的问题
So for
因此为了
example if I have something that is horizontally compact I
例如如果我有一些水平紧凑
draw those two red arrows and where is that, well
我画这两个红色箭头在这里，
look down at the bottom of the screen here it says any any.
看屏幕下方的 any any 这个区域
So this is the user interface if you're in any any
这个用户界面如果你在任意
the default user interface okay.
默认的用户界面
If I click on this right here I can pick any of
如果我点击右边这里我可以挑出这些
those nine boxes that I showed on that slide.
九个盒子就我在幻灯片显示的
So for example look at this box right here.
例如看在这里的这个盒子
This is any width but a compact height.
这个任意宽度但是紧凑的高
Now when I click here its actually gonna change my user
现在当我点击这里它的确改变了我们的用户
interface and show me what the user interface looks like on
界面并且给我们在设备上展示这个用户界面
a device that is any width but a compact height.
这设备是任意宽但是紧凑的高
See, these are just two labels I threw out here that do
看，这里有两个标签去作为
that and same thing let's say over here, any height,
相同事物让我们展示这里，任意高
compact width.
紧凑的宽
Or, over here we have regular width, any height.
或者这里普通的宽，任意高
And over here we have any width,
这里我们用任意宽
regular height, yeah, there we go.
整齐的高，好，继续
So that's it.
就这样
That's my entire user interface.
这是我们整体的用户界面
I just put the arrows in whichever SizeClass was
我只是在 SizeClass 上放箭头
appropriate there.
在合适的位置上
This is really cool to be able to go here and basically edit
这实在是酷能够到达这里，并且有基本编辑
your user interface in any of these circumstances.
在这些任何状况下在你的用户界面里
Including specific ones,
在这些特殊的情况下
like this Compact Width Compact Height.
就像这个紧凑的宽紧凑的高
That's basically, you're editing your user
这是最基本的，你在编辑的你的用户
interface for non-iPhone 6 Pluses in Landscape.
界面在横屏非 iPhone 6 plus 上
Because that's the only one that is both Compact Width and
因为那是只有一个全部紧凑宽
Compact Height.
和紧凑高
Okay?
下一步？
So you could actually have a specific one just for
隐藏你们的确可以有一个特殊的在
that circumstance.
特定状况下
Okay? But it's nicer to
下一步？但是非常好去使用
have these Anys, to use these Anys out here so
这些 Any，使用 Any 使
that they'll work, and we'll see in the demo.
他们运行，我们将在演示中见到的
And one of the things I challenged,
有一个我们改变的事物
I didn't really talk about it in the slides there,
我没有在幻灯片里讨论
but I challenged you to do is, I actually added this as an
但是我期待你去做，我给做出作业3的额外的分数
extra credit to the homework number three, if you want.
如果你们想的话
Go back and
回去
make your calculator user interface look different.
让你们的计数器与众不同
In different SizeClasses.
在不同的 SizeClasses
Maybe do five buttons by four instead of four by five,
可能是五列四行替代了四列五行
okay, or something like that.
当然或者其他的
Or even, some ones have more buttons.
也可以加更多的按键
If you look at the calculator that Apple ships on
你看 Apple 商城的计算器
the iPhone, when you go to Landscape,
当你横屏看的时候
it has a lot more operations.
它有更多的操作
The buttons are all smaller, but
这些按键更小，但是
it has a lot of operations that aren't even there.
有更多的操作在那里
And you can do that with side classes as well.
你可以用 side classes 去实现这些
Okay, alright so
当然
now we're gonna write an app here from scratch.
现在我们将用 scratch 写一个应用
And it is going to look like this.
它将看起来像这个
Okay here's what it's UIs gonna look like.
这些 UI 看起来像这样的
It's very, very, this is a demo, okay,
他非常非常，这就是一个演示
so it's a very simple app.
一个很简单的应用
It asks for a username and password up here, so
它请求帐号密码
I have madbum, and password is foo.
我有登录密码
Now, I can change the security on my password.
我更改这个密码的安全性
I can have it be secured so I can't see it, okay.
我可以使其可靠，让我看不到它
But when I log in, it's gonna show me.
但是当我登录，它将会显示
An icon for the person,
一个面向用户的图标
the persons name, and what company they work for, okay.
用户的名字他们工作的公司
Madison Bumgarner in this case.
Madison Bumgarner 也在那
And if I rotate it's gonna say the same information but
如果我旋转它将显示这些相同的信息但是
notice that this is not below here,
这个并不在下方
it's actually moved to be beside it.
它被移除去了
Okay?
下一步？
So, basically, on Sizeclasses that are regular height, or
因此，基本的，SizeClasses 是普通高或者
have a lot of room, I put the words at the bottom.
有很多空间，我放很多单词在下面
I try to use this space to show their picture more.
我尝试用这些空间去显示更多的照片
And in other SizeClasses, I put it off to the side, okay?
在另外一个 SizeClasses，我把它放到另一边
And we have other users here, like, Same password.
我们有其他的用户在这里，就像，相同的密码
Okay it's all got all the different icon or old j apple.
它得到所有不同的图标或者 japple
Okay John Appleseed.
John Appleseed
Okay? In all of these cases
下一步？这些所有的情况下
it's going to do that.
它将这么做
Okay so lot going on here to make this work with
很多将在这使其运作通过
auto layout.
自动布局
Right you got
你所得到的正确的方式
this thing automatically changing right here.
这个自动化地在这里改变
You've got this you've got this image here which you
你将得到这个图片
want to be the right aspect ration.
这图片是你将在正确方面配给
You know we got he SizeClass things so
你知道你得到 SizeClass 图片
we can put the words underneath when it's tall etc.
所以我们可以放这些单词到下面当它很高等
Okay.
好的
So that's what we're going to build.
因此我们将建立这个
Alright, let's go and we're going to start from
好的，让我们开始
scratch as I like to do usually, so
从 scratch 就像我们通常做的那样
it's creating a new XCode project, iOS application.
它创建一个新的 xcode 项目，iOS 应用
I'm going to call it auto layout, okay.
我将称它为自动布局
I'm going to put it the same place I put all of my
我将放在同一个位置我放在所有
apps there.
我的应用那里
Here it is.
就这里
I'm gonna move this app delegate out of the way.
我将不用这个方式移动这个应用
And the launch screen out of the way.
不用这个方式登录界面
For the first time we're actually gonna
第一次我们将
talk about these image assets here today.
告诉这些图片连接这个地方
It's a good opportunity to talk about that.
这是一个很好的机会阐述这个
Okay. And in my controller,
好，在我的控制下
I'm gonna clear out this code.
我将清理这些代码
Don't need any of that.
并不需要这么做
By the way, the things that I cleared out here,
顺便说一下，这个我清理的地方
you starting to recognize them?
你开始认出他们？
View controller life cycle methods.
视图控制器生命周期方法
Okay.
好的
But if I need those, I'll put them back but okay.
但是我需要这些，我将他们放回去
So, let's go to our storyboard and start building this UI.
让我们到这个 storyboard 并且开始建立这个 UI
Now this is gonna be a lot of clicking things around.
现在这里将有很多点击事物在周围
I'm gonna make this as big as possible for us here.
我将使这些在这里尽可能大的显示
That's all right, that there.
Lot of graphical things happening.
Let's just do that.
Okay, so I'm gonna start with those text fields at
the top, right?
I need a username and password text field.
So I'm gonna go down here and grab a text field.
Okay, this is actually gonna be an editable one, so
I grab this one, text, not label, but text.
And I'm going to put it up in the upper corner to start.
Grab another one, put this here.
Okay, now, I'm gonna use some model layout stuff you
already know about.
I'm gonna use Ctrll drag.
Let's stick this one trailing space to that edge.
Let's stick this one with this trailing space to that end.
Let's get this one to the top.
Let's put a space in
between the vertical space between them.
You know about.
Doing all those kind of things.
Now one thing as I'm working with auto layout I
often like to click this little button right here.
Because this will
give you a little summary of what's going on.
And when all it's complaining about is that frames are gonna
be moved, a cool thing you can do is go down here
to this button.
The same one where we do Reset to Suggested Constraints and
Clear Constraints, there's this Update Frame.
And it will update all frames in your storyboard.
Now, it made those smaller because the text in
them is small, but don't worry about that.
We're gonna fix that later.
So I did Undo right there because I wanted them to be
a little bigger just as I work.
Okay? But I'll be going back to
look at this often.
And if I see it's just frames,
then I'll be doing Update Frames.
And if I don't like what it did I
can always undo, keep going.
All right?
So let's go and do our things here for
the user name and password fields.
So I'm just going to put some text in these.
Password.
User name, so
these ones I kind of want to be on the left.
Okay, if you remember.
So I'm gonna do the same thing here with control drag.
Let's set that leaning space.
Let's set this thing to the,
actually I'm not even gonna set this to the top.
Now this is an interesting one.
So I have these two guys right here.
Really what I want them to do is be lined up with whatever
the text is in here.
I wanna line them up by their baselines.
So I'm gonna control drag between the two of them and
go down here and pick Baseline.
So this is going to line up their baselines.
Okay?
Same thing here, drag this one.
And line up their baselines there.
Now, another thing I want is that I want them to be kind
of, well, I want these two guys, username and
password, to be the same width.
So, I'm control dragging between them and
saying Equal Widths.
You remember in the calculator we
did the equal widths down here with this thing, okay?
But, you can do it with control drag as well.
And then also I want these things attached.
So I want that thing attached to each other so
that its horizontal spacing is set.
And I want this thing attached to this,
its horizontal spacing.
Now I've done all this stuff even though
they're really not where I want them right now.
So usually you can kinda set things up and
then just go into the size inspector.
And inspect all of them and
get rid of every magic number you see.
If you get rid of every magic number you see usually it's
gonna do exactly what you want.
So lets go here, lets start with this one.
Lets find some magic numbers.
Look at this Leading Space Username.
[SOUND] Magic number.
Okay magic number means number in here,
anything that's a number get rid of it.
So 392 I'm gonna get rid of that,
I'm gonna do it by going up here.
Instead of having 392,
I'm going to pick Standard Value, okay?
So now it's gone.
So you can click on these things and
click Edit to get rid of these.
点击编辑来去掉他们
Even 8, which had got by the blue lines, okay?
即使是8，是通过蓝色的线条来得到的，明白？
I don't like that either.
我同样也不喜欢那个
I'm just going to go here and say zero, because
我将要到这里并说0，因为
I want that to be right up against the edge, okay?
我想要挨着那个边界，明白？
Oops. Sorry.
哦，对不起
Same thing, oh, did I do the right thing there?
同样的，我在这里做的对么？
Leading space, username, yeah, trailing spaces, you're right.
距离顶部的空间，用户名，好的，距离底部的空间，你是对的
How about this one?
这个怎么样？
Top Space to Top Layout right here,
这里就是顶部布局的顶部空间
I'll use the Standard Value for that.
我将对它们使用默认的值
Okay?
明白？
Oops, sorry, keep clicking there.
哦，对不起，继续点击那里
And then here, Align Baseline equals three.
然后在这里，距离基线的距离等于3
Okay I want these baselines exactly aligned not three off
好的我想要这些基线的实际距离不为3
of each other so I'm gonna say zero right here.
所以我准备在这里设置为0
So I've gotten rid of all the magic numbers in here.
Okay now lets do it for
this one, okay this one also has a magic number here,
lets change that to be Standard Value.
We got this one, Align Baseline.
We want that to be zero.
Okay? So we got rid of that.
How about this one?
Oh, this one's good.
No magic value.
And this one, also good.
Okay? All is good.
All is well with the world.
Okay?
But we still have this up here.
Frame will be different at run time, so
I'm going to go down here.
And update our frames and this looks good.
Now, when I look at this I'm like that's really not what I
want, so I must have made a mistake.
For example, I want this spacing in-between not to
be zero, so
I typed zero somewhere where I wanted a standard value.
So, let's go back here and see where that is.
Okay? It looks like it's this one
you can tell when you mouse over these, it tells you.
So here let's go back to here and
instead of zero, let's say Standard Value, okay?
And it moved it there for us.
Sometimes it moves it,
sometimes you need to do update frames.
It just kind of depends on
the character of the change you're making.
Okay?
Now, here's a really cool thing.
I want to see what
this looks like in portrait and landscape.
So yeah, I could go up here and hit Run,
but there is a lot faster way, which is to open up
the assistant editor here and instead of showing your view
controller, go up here and go down to Preview.
This will preview your UI.
Okay? And you can preview it in
either landscape or portrait.
You can also preview it on other devices like
maybe an iPhone 6 Plus, okay, which is kind of so
big that we can't barely even see it here.
Barely flip it around, okay?
Or you can even look at it on an iPad if you wanted.
Okay I think four inches works best for
this small resolution I have.
But this is really cool, now this can only preview your UI
for things that aren't running your code.
Okay so if you're gonna do something that you need to
run your code then you need to go run it in the app.
But if you just want to
see how is the auto layout gonna work.
You can do this.
Now another thing that's cool here is what's this gonna look
like when you give it off to your localization guys and
if this gets translated to German or something like that.
You can do that, you can kinda make sure that you
don't have any big problems by going down here,
see where it says English.
Sort of click on that.
And we can go to this double length pseudo language.
And all that does is doubles every text.
Okay? So even a long translation of
the word Username would fit there.
And my auto layout is working properly.
And so my translation is just going to work.
So Auto Layout is not just used for
landscape versus portrait or whatever.
It can be used for translation as well.
When you're localizing things,
you want auto-layout to make things fit.
Okay? Everyone understand that?
Okay.
All right, good.
So we're making progress here.
By the way, you probably don't wanna have preview open as
you're doing a lot of changes here,
cuz it's gonna be constantly previewing in real time.
So if you've got a really powerful machine,
it could keep up, but
you might be asking it to do a lot of calculations.
So I usually close that while I'm working, and
then just bring it back whenever I wanna preview.
So let's do those two buttons.
Remember, I had the button change security,
which changed this to secure, and
then I had the button login, so let's go ahead and do that.
Another trick I'm going to show you is, and
I'm always scrolling around in here trying to find things.
You can actually find things real quick by going down to
the bottom here and typing like button.
Now it's only going to show you the buttons.
Okay? We got Bar Button and
here's regular button, so I'm going to drag that out.
Let's get a couple of those buttons.
We'll call this one Change security.
We'll call this one log in.
Okay now where do these want to be?
They kind of
want to be underneath there something like that.
Definitely I like their baselines lined
up right there.
So let's go ahead and kind of put those in position.
I'm gonna set the vertical spacing between the login and
this guy right here and
then I'm control dragging here to set the baselines the same.
Okay?
Now, that has actually set the vertical position of both of
these things, okay.
Because the vertical position of these are set and so
when I tie this vertical position here and
the baseline which is a vertical positioning here but
if I go up here it says that the horizontal position of
Login and Change Security is ambiguous.
Which makes sense.
I haven't really specified where these
things are supposed to be.
Just because I put them on
the screen doesn't mean that there's an auto layout rule.
Now, what do I want it to be?
Well, I kind of want them to be some reasonable distance
apart so it doesn't look like, you know,
this is part of the same thing.
That would look like change security log in is one thing.
So I want them apart a little bit.
But otherwise I want them centered on the screen.
I want the pair of them centered.
Now, there's no auto layout rule that says that.
That's too complicated, okay?
But, I can easily do this with a little creativity, and
when you start doing auto layout,
you start realizing, hm, how can I do that?
Well, I need to be creative in how I'm gonna approach this.
[NOISE] And in this case what I'm gonna do is
I'm gonna create two little spacer views on the side here.
And I'm gonna set them to be the same width.
Can you see how that's gonna make it so
these two kinda get pushed into the middle?
Right, by the same amount on each side.
So how would I do that?
So I'm gonna do that by just grabbing some views,
just generic views,
okay, this just a generic view like the one you do to
do your graph view or the face view or whatever.
When I'm working on it here, I'm going to give it
some background color so I can see the thing, okay,
now when I'm actually ready to go I will turn that back off.
And I'm just going to put them in here somewhere, copy and
paste another one, put it over here somewhere, and
then I'm just gonna wire these up to how I want them,
so I want this to kind of be on that edge,
I want this thing to be on that edge,
I want these two things to kind of be linked.
Okay.
Let's say I'll link their horizontal spacing.
Now here, I'm going to
set multiple things between these two.
I'm gonna set the horizontal spacing and
then notice I'm holding down shift.
I'm also gonna set the top and
bottom of this view to match the top and bottom.
Now, there's no base lines because this is not text.
This is just a generic view.
So I'm gonna move mine up the top and bottom.
So I can do Shift+click to do that.
Okay. And then same thing over here,
I'm gonna do the same thing with these two guys.
I'm gonna set the top whoops, sorry, control drag.
I'm gonna set the top and bottom horizontal spacing.
Okay.
Then I said I wanted to make this one and
this one be equal widths.
So I can just do that with control drag as well, so
I've set that up.
I want this to be stuck to this edge, trailing space,
I want this to be stuck to this edge, leading space, and
I want these two guys to have some horizontal spacing,
I'm not quite sure how much I want yet, but
I want some sort of horizontal spacing.
Now, I've done this, and look, the yellow thing went away.
It says, okay, I know exactly where to put these things.
这个意思是Xcode已经知道这几个组件的确切位置了。
But this is really not where I want these put, okay?
但是这个不是我想要的确切位置。
Because I actually want this spacer right up against this,
因为我希望这个贴着这个，
and I want this spacer right up against this.
这个贴着这个。
So I'm gonna go through that same process again of
所以我要再做一次同样的事情来消除那些
getting rid of the magic number.
魔法数。
So let's start with this guy.
从这个开始。
And get rid of his magic numbers in the size inspector,
在尺寸检查器里消除掉它的魔法数。
so it's got this trailing space here,
来到尾部间距这里，
let's get rid of that.
消除掉它。
We want that to be a standard value.
我们希望它是标准值。
Okay we got this one, we align the bottoms we want those to
到这里，它们应该底部是对齐的，
be exactly aligned, so we'll do zero.
所以这个应该是0.
Same thing with top we want that exactly aligned, so
顶部应该也是对齐的，
I got rid of all of the magic numbers for this.
这样魔法数就全没了。
How about this guy?
继续这个。
Same thing.
还是一样的
Okay? We want this to be standard value.
这我希望是标准值。
Usually I always put it to standard value
通常来说我都会选标准值，
unless standard value is not an option.
但是当标准值不能选时，
Then I usually pick zero.
我一般就选0.
Okay? If standard value is
如果标准值不可用，
not an option I'll just make it zero.
我就把它设成0.
Then here, a line top.
这里，顶部对齐，
Let's see. Standard value, nope.
选标准值，不行。
Let's make it zero.
那就是0吧。
Okay?
So, no magic numbers there.
魔法数没了。
How about this guy?
继续下一个。
Does he have magic numbers?
这个有魔法数吗？
Yeah, he has this 87.
有一个87.
That's this difference between these two.
这个跟前边的就不同了。
That's okay.
这个是可以的。
This has a magic number here.
这里还有一个魔法数。
This.
这个
Hello.
Standard value.
标准值。
Okay. So now,
the only magic number we have is this 87,
好了，所以现在唯一的魔法数就是这个87了。
which is this distance here.
是这两个之间的距离。
Now, what's really cool about this is you can
这里一个非常酷的东西是，
double click on this.
你可以双击这里。
And inspect it right in space.
就可以看到它们的间距。
So here I'm gonna make it be let's say 50.
我要把它设成50.
So this is a magic number right here, because there's
这是一个魔法数，因为
really no standard spacing cuz I'm kinda doing somewhat of
这里并没有一个标准的间距，我们正在做的并不是
a non standard thing here.
一个标准化的东西。
Any time you do a non standard thing,
每当你要做一个非标准化的东西的时候，
really ask yourself do I really want to be doing this?
都要问一下自己是不是确定。
Okay cuz I'm kinda going against the grain by doing
要确定自己做的是不是确实需要
something against, you know, what standard values are.
与标准值不同。
In this case I'm gonna go ahead and do it, but I should
在这里，我确实需要怎么做，但是
probably be asking myself if I really wanna do that.
也应该问一下自己是否确定。
And it might be a little confusing to users.
因为这有可能会让使用者迷惑。
So let's go ahead and
现在咱们继续，
look at this thing in the preview again.
在预览里再看一下。
So here it is, looks good, see,
看上去没什么问题，看。
it made those two things the same width,
这两个辅助的视图宽度是一样的，
put these things in the center.
把它们两个置于中间。
Same thing here, put those in the center, excellent.
横过来，也是一样的，在中间，非常好。
Okay?
So, that's good.
非常好。
Now, I've got it where I want it.
我觉得已经达到目的了。
So I can go back and
现在我需要回去
turn these things back to being non gray, okay?
把这两个辅助视图的灰色去掉，
Go back to the default.
回到默认状态就好。
Okay?
See how I built that UI?
看到我是怎么构建这个UI的了吗？
So those spacers, don't forget you can put spacers in.
不要忘了你可以用辅助视图，
They're perfectly legal to throw in there.
把它们扔在那是完全没有问题的。
Question?
有问题么？
>> So what's the canvas option?
画布选项是什么？
[INAUDIBLE] you choose the canvas value?
［不清楚］选画布值是什么意思？
>> Okay. Yeah. When you have something selected.
我明白了，如果你选了一个组件。
Okay?
And you go over here and it says Edit, and
点到这里，
you can change to the Canvas Value,
你可以选择画布值，
that says whatever is actually here right now.
意思就是在你看到的实际效果，
In other words, to what I moved it to, basically.
换句话说，就是我把它挪到的位置。
And when you first Ctrl+drag,
就是你第一次Ctrl＋拖拽时
that's the value it's gonna have, okay?
的实际值。
Good question there.
非常好的问题。
Okay.
Now let's start writing some code, okay?
现在我们开始写代码。
Cuz I want this change security button to
我希望摁change security这个摁钮可以
change this to say secured password.
可以让这里显示为secured password。
And I want this to
同时我也希望
actually be a secured password in that case, 'kay?
输入的密码变成星号。
So what is that code gonna look like?
代码应该是什么样的呢。
Let's go here to automatic.
这里我们选自动。
Here's our view controller here.
这里就是我们的视图控制器。
I'm gonna need some outlets to connect to these things.
这里我需要outlet连接一下组件。
So I'm gonna Ctrl+drag some stuff here.
在这里ctrl＋拖拽。
Let's control + drag that.
先拖这个，
That is our login field.
这是我们的登陆框。
Let's control + drag this.
再拖这个，
That is our password field.
这是密码框。
And let's control + drag over to this.
再拖这个，
That is our password label, okay.
这是密码标签。
So we got that.
搞定。
Now.
Lets say I'm going to do my viewDidLoad() here, okay, and
下边我要实现viewDidLoad()方法，我需要
when my view is loaded I'm going to update my UI,、
在我的视图载入的时候更新我的UI。
well first of all,
啊，首先，
of course, I'm going to do super.viewDidLoad().
我当然需要写 super.viewDidLoad()。
Then I'm gonna update my UI.
然后我要更新我的UI。
Gonna make this wider so
把这个弄宽一点，
this is not jumping out on you so much.
不至于经常换行。
I'm not gonna have a private func here to update my UI.
我这里要实现一个私有方法来更新我的UI。
And all I'm gonna do in my UI so
目前我要对UI做的事儿是，
far is, I'm gonna have that password field.
我需要把密码框的
I'm gonna set its secure text entry to true.
文字加密输入设为真，
Or actually, I'm gonna set it to secure.
事实上我要设成 secure 。
And I'm gonna have a var for that.
因为我要有一个变量。
So let's have a var here called secure.
这里写一个叫 secure 的变量。
It's gonna be boolean.
是布尔类型。
Actually don't even need to say that.
实际上不需要定义类型，
Let's say it's false.
给它设为 false 。
It starts out false and I'm gonna do a did set here and
它初始值时false，我要加一个didSet，这样的话，每次它的
update my UI every time it changes.
值变化的时候就会更新UI。
And I'm gonna allow this to be public so
我要把它设为公共的，这样
people can set this boolean secure.
别人就可以设置它的布尔值。
And what's the problem here?
啊，这出什么问题了？
Oh computer property must have that there's something
哦，计算属性必须。。。好像是哪
wrong there.
错了。
Well but that okay.
好了。
So, I'm going to let people set this secure thing externally, and
这里我允许其他人从外部设置这个值，
then that's going to change this to say secure password,
然后可以改变这个标签里的文本为 secure password，
and it's going to start securing it here.
这里也会变成星号。
So, we're going to do secure text entry.
现在我们看这个文本加密输入，
This is just a property in UI text field that you can set,
这只是一个你可以设置的UITextField的属性，
that just makes it so
效果就是
that when you type, you get the little dots instead of
当是输入的时候，你会看到星号，而不是
seeing what the person is typing.
明文。
And then I'm also going to,
下边要做的是，
in the password label, I'm going to set its text.
密码标签，我要设置它的文本，
If it's secure, I'm going to set it to be secured password.
如果密码是加密的，我需要让它显示 secured password。
And if it's not secure,
如果不是，
I'm going to set it to just be password.
它就显示 password 就好了。
Okay. So
that's this label right here.
就是这个标签。
I'm going to change that label depending on whether
我要根据密码是否为加密输入来改变
it's secure or not.
它的文本。
Does that make sense?
明白了吗？
All right. So let's go ahead and
好，我们继续，
run because now we need to run,
来运行一下，
because we're going to be executing our code here.
看看刚才写的代码是不是可以执行。
Let's hope that when we click that button,
我希望当我摁这个摁钮的时候，
our autolayout makes it so
我们的自动布局
that everything kind of shifts over and
会做出相应的位移改变。
it doesn't because we need to have a target action.
并没有，因为我们还需要一个target action。
Let's do target action here, we want an action method.
弄一个target action，这里需要一个方法。
We'll call this toggleSecurity.
我们叫它toggleSecurity。
Don't need an argument there,、
不需要参数。
connect, here's toggleSecurity.
点connect，这就是toggleSecurity。
And this is secure equals not secure.
这里写 secure ＝ !secure
Okay, we're just gonna toggle the security on that
当我们摁这个摁钮的时候，
when this button is pressed.
我们需要改变这个布尔值
[SOUND].
Okay. So, change security.
好，点这个摁钮。
Looks good. And see how it
很好，注意到
moved these things?
组件是如何移动的了吗？
We had equal widths set on these, so
两个输入框是等宽的，
when I changed security it makes these
当我摁这个摁钮的时候，
be equal widths which moves everything else out of
两个等宽的输入框就会相应的调整尺寸，
the way as necessary and it works either way.
横屏也没有问题。
Okay? Everybody cool with that?
大家都能明白吗？
Alright, so next let's do login right here.
下边我们做登陆功能。
Okay, so the login is real easy.
登陆非常简单。
I'm just going to go over here and Ctrl+drag for
我只需要ctrl＋拖拽一个 target action。
target action.
We'll call this login.
给这个方法起名叫 login 。
It's an action.
这是一个动作。
Oops, sorry got that wrong.
不好意思选错了。
Let's us go over here.
从这开始拖，
Ctrl+drag, an action, called login.
一个动作，起名login。
We don't need the sender.
不需要sender。
Connect.
连接。
Now how am I going to do login?
我要怎么实现登陆呢？
Well, I actually have a simple user class which I
我要把一个简单的user类拖进
am going to drag into here.
项目里来。
Here it is right here.
在这。
User.swift, okay.
User.swift
So I'm going drag that into, oops.
要把它拖进来，啊哦。。
Lets go here.
往这边挪一下。
Easiest way to do this.
最简单的办法，
All right, so I'm just gonna drag User.swift in here.
把User.swift拖进来。
I'm gonna copy it.
需要拷贝它。
There we go.
好了。
Okay, what does the User.swift look like?
User.swift 长什么样呢？
Looks like this.
这样的。
It's a model class it doesn't has nothing to do with UI.
这是一个model类，跟UI毫无关系。
It's just model class.
仅仅是一个model类。
And it just has name, company, login and password.
只有姓名，公司，用户名和密码。
And it has a function,
这有一个方法，
just a class function here that you can use to log-in.
一个用来登陆的类方法。
And it has a little database of users like
这有一个小的用户的数据库，比如
Madison Bumgarner.
Madison Bumgarner。
Okay. So that's all that's in there.
这就是全部了。
Let's go use that now, in our controller.
接下来我们要在视图控制器里用它。
So when I log in,
当我点登陆的时候
I'm just going to set my set a loggedInUser so I need some
我就需要设置我的 loggedInUser，
var which is a logged in user, that's basically my model.
所以我要写一个loggedInUser变量，就是我的model。
LoggedInUser, it's going to be a user.
loggedInUser，user类型。
And I'm going to do the didSet.
加一个didSet。
Actually it's going to be user optional.
应该是一个可选变量，
And I'm going to do my didSet here, and also updateUI.
现在我要写我的didSet，也是 updateUI 。
So if anyone changes my logged in user externally,
如果有人从外部改变了我的 loggedInUser，
I'll let this be public, then I can update my UI.
这个变量是公共的，然后我可以更新我的UI。
And finally, say loggedInUser equals User.login.
最后，我要写 loggedInUser ＝ User.login。
And now I need to give it the login,
现在我要给login参数。
that's this field right here.
就是输入框里的文本。
So I'm going to say loginField.text.
所以这里写 loginField.text 。
But this could be an optional.
这个应该是可选的。
Okay?
And the user takes a string.
这是一个字符串参数。
So, I'm gonna say, okay, well, if it's nil, if
所以我这里写，如果它为空，
the log-in fill is nil, then just pass blank empty string.
如果输入框的文本为空，我就传入一个空字符串。
Okay?
That's obviously not gonna log into anything,
很明显这样就不会登陆，
but that's okay.
但是是允许的。
And then, same thing here; passwordField.text.
这里也是一样的，passwordField.text 。
And we'll have empty string there as well, kay?
也需要可选一个空字符串。
So, that's how we're gonna log in, and
这就是我们如何实现登陆的，
we'll have a loggedInUser.
通过 loggedInUser 变量。
Once we have our updateUI here that's,
还需要在 updateUI 里加入，
actually we'll do that a little later.
这个等一会再做。
Okay.
So, that's it, okay?
就先这样。
So, now we got logged in, we got this whole part of our
现在我们有了登陆功能，就有了全部的
user interface working right here.
用户界面。
Now about the bottom part.
下边要做底部的部分。
The bottom we had an image and
底部应该有一个图片，
we had the name of the person and
一个人名和他所在
the company they worked for.
的公司。
So let's do the image first.
我们先搞图片部分。
I'm just going to go over here and grab an image.
我直接到这里选一个 image。
I'm going to go up here.
到这里。
I'm going to type image, and this is a class,
输入image，这个是一个跟 UILabel 很
kind of like a UI label for images, called image view.
类似的类，叫做 image view。
I'm going to put this in the corner down here.
把它放在左下角。
And we Ctrl+dragged, leading space,
ctrl＋拖拽，左间距，
Ctrl+drag, bottom space.
ctrl＋拖拽，底部间距，
Now, you'd think, oh, I just set this here, it's ready to
这时你会觉得，我已经固定了它的位置，
go, but when I click this little thing it says, oh,
但是当我点这个黄三角的时候，
the size and vertical position are ambiguous for imageView.
它说这个imageView的尺寸和垂直距离不确定。
And that's because we don't have an image in here so
因为我们还没往里面放一个图片，
it doesn't know what size it is.
所以不知道尺寸应该有多大。
Okay, so let's put an image in here and
那我们就放一个图片进去，
I got some images we can use right here.
这有一些准备好的图片。
Okay, so I'm going to bring this image Stanford into my project.
这里我准备把这张斯坦福的图片拖进我们的项目。
This is the first time we have done this and
这是我们第一次这么做，
this is what this image.xcassests is for.
image.xcassests是管理你app
This manages all your images in your app.
里所有图片的东西。
Here's my app icon, I have not set it to anything so
这是我app的图标，我还没有图标所以
those are all blank.
这里是空的。
I'm going to to drag this Stanford image in here and
把斯坦福的图片拖到这里来，
it creates it.
新建了一个图片。
Now, notice this says 1x, so that means on
注意这有一个1x，意思是这个图片
low resolution devices this is the image it's gonna use.
是用于低分辨率的设备的。
And I could actually have
实际上我可以在
a different image on a higher resolution device.
高分辨率设备上有一个完全不同的图片。
Like maybe on a high resolution device I could do
比如在高分辨率设备上，我可以
this one with the Stanford tree.
用这个斯坦福树的图片。
I have more resolution, so
分辨率高了，
I can draw this little tree a little better.
所以我可以给图片多加一棵树。
Okay, and on a really high res device like maybe iPhone 6
在像iPhone 6 plus这样分辨率极高的
plus I could put even higher resolution image in there.
设备上我们可以用分辨率更高的图片。
So you can manage that.
所以我们可以很好的管理图片。
You can also manage other things about the images.
你还可以通过其他的方式管理图片，
I'm not really gonna go into this, but
这里我不准备细讲，你可以通过
you can manage them by size class.
size classes管理它们。
Okay, this image appears on compact or
可以让图片在compact或者
regular or whatever.
regular下显示。
It also has vector graphics in addition to bitmaps.
还可以选择矢量图或者位图。
It's a really powerful system for
确实是一个非常强大的管理你app里
managing all of your image assets here.
所有图片的系统。
Now around here I'm gonna go ahead and
下边我要继续拖一些其他
drag some of these other images I have in here as well.
的图片进来。
Cuz we'll need those later.
之后会用到。
Okay, here's all my images I have down here.
好了，这就是我要用到的全部图片。
Okay, so I have an image.
我有了图片，
So how do I set the image of this little thing in
那么我如何把图片放到我的
my storyboard?
storyboard里来呢？
Well, I just inspect this image view and go here.
我只需要选中这个imageview， 选择检视器。
And all the images I just loaded are gonna be here.
我刚才拖进来的图片全在这了。
So I'm gonna pick Stanford, okay?
这里我选斯坦福。
So, now that I've given an image, look No problems.
我给了它一张图片，看这里，没问题了。
It just says the frame is wrong.
它只是说frame是错的。
So no problem, let's fix the frame.
这个没问题，我们只需要修复一下frame就好了。
Oops.
额。。
There. Update frames.
这里，update frames。
Oh, ew, that's no good.
额。这什么情况。
Okay.
So we have a big image there, smashes on top of the other
图片好大，盖住了其他东西。
thing, so how are we gonna fix that?
我们怎么修复这个问题？
Well, a simple way to do that would be just to
一个简单的办法就是
Ctrl+drag between these two and set the vertical spacing.
按住 Ctrl 拖动，设置他们的垂直间距
Okay? And then I
看到了吗？
can even double click this and
我也可以双击它
make this vertical spacing be a standard value.
把垂直间距设置成一个标准值
Okay? Now, let's go ahead and
懂了吗？
update frames.
现在我们来 Update Frames（更新框架）
And it doesn't smash into the ones on top.
它并没有挤压到上面的元素
Okay?
OK?
Simple solution there.
很简单的解决方案
But we still have this right here.
但是我们仍然有一个警告
Eight views are vertically ambiguous.
8个 view 在垂直方向会产生歧义
Oh my gosh!
我的天！
What did I do?
我都做什么了？
It looks perfect to me.
这看起来很完美啊
Why is it saying that?
它为什么会有这个警告呢？
Well, when you get this kinda thing, it's time to go back to
如果有类似这种警告
our old friend, the document outline here, okay.
就应该到 Document Outline 去检查一下
Let's make some more space.
把程序最大化
In the document outline,
在 Document Outline 中
we can click on this thing in the corner here.
我们可以点击角落里的这个按钮
And look at all these problems we have.
可以看到出现的所有问题
Okay, you can see that it's all these vertical things
它们都是关于垂直布局的问题
here, understandably, and look what it keeps suggesting.
我们来具体看看它的建议
Oh, set the vertical
哦
compression resistance priority.
设置 Compression Resistance Priority
Set the vertical hugging.
设置 Vertical Hugging
What the heck is compression resistance priority and
Compression Resistance Priority 和 Vertical Hugging
vertical hugging?
是什么？
What the heck is that?
它们到底是什么？
Okay?
OK?
That has to do with this user interface is going to
它们可以使得 UI
be expanding and compressing vertically.
在垂直方向扩张或者压缩
And when it does, who gets the extra space?
当扩张时，谁能获取额外空间？
And when it compresses down, who allows themselves to
当压缩时，谁允许它们被压缩
be compressed, and who can't compress?
谁又不能压缩？
Okay?
OK？
That's what this hugging and
这就是 Hugging
compression resistance is about.
和 Compression Resistance 的作用
So, here we've got, these guys are all lined up.
这些元素都已经设置好了
This, okay, these two guys, and
这两个元素和这个按钮
this button, they can not be compressed.
它们不能被压缩
If they get compressed,
如果它们被压缩了
their text is gonna get squished down.
它们上面的文字就会被挤压
So, we do not want them compressed.
所以我们不希望这些元素被压缩
But this guy, he could be compressed.
但是这个元素，它可以被压缩
Because it's an image,
因为它是一张图片
it can just redraw itself at a shorter height.
它可以以一个较短的高度重绘自己
So, I need to set the resistance to being compressed
所以我需要把阻力设置成可以被压缩
for this guy to be lower.
对于这个图片，设置地低一些
You've got to lower resistance to being compressed.
把可以被压缩的指数设置地低一些
So how do I do that?
我该怎么做呢？
You do that in the Size Inspector.
你可以去到 Size INspector
If you select something, you'll see down here at
如果你选中了某个元素
the bottom, Content Hugging Priority and
可以看到底部有 Content Hugging Priority
Content Compression Resistance Priority.
和 Content Compression Resistance Priority
Okay? Now, these are priorities.
这些就是 Priority
These are just arbitrary numbers.
它们都用数字代表
Right now, this one is 750 in the vertical.
这个元素在垂直方向的 Priority 是 750
This one is also 750.
这个也是 750
This one is 750.
这个是 750
They all have the same priority to be compressed.
它们的压缩系数都是一样的
That's why it's complaining, okay?
这就是为什么 Xcode 会有这些警告
Cuz it doesn't know which one to compress,
因为它不知道该压缩哪一个
cuz they're all the same.
因为它们的数值都是相同的
So we can just go back to this one and say, okay well,
现在我们选择这个 ImageView
we're gonna lower this guy's compression resistance to 700.
我要把它的压缩系数降到 700
Oh, all my problems went away.
所有问题都不见了
Okay? Now I
看到了吗？
have no yellow thing up here.
这里已经没有黄色的警告了
This resolved everything.
这一个修改解决了所有问题
I had eight things that were ambiguous.
曾经有8个有歧义的东西
Now they're all fine.
现在都没有问题了
Why? Because, when we compress now,
为什么呢？因为压缩的时候
we're gonna know that this is the guy who gets compressed,
系统已经知道该压缩哪个元素了
and these guys don't.
其它元素就不需要被压缩了
Okay? So that's what the compression
这就是有关于压缩的事情
thing, and we'll see hugging in in a second, and com, and
稍后我们会讲到 Hugging
more compression a little later, okay?
和更多与 Compression 相关的
So that's what these are about.
这就是相关的东西
A lot of people are, like,
许多人会说
well, I don't understand these.
我不理解这些东西
But it's quite simple.
但是这些概念真的很简单
It's just how much is this view,
它只是一个与其它 view 对比的值
compared to other views, resisting being compressed?
数值越大代表越不希望被压缩
And hugging priority is,
Hugging Priority 是
how much does it want to be its size?
它有多希望变得更小
How much does it want to be small, in other words?
换句话说，你到底想不想变小
So, like this guy always, that button always wants to
好比这个按钮
be only big enough to hold the login.
它总是希望能装下 Login 这几个字符
It does not want to be really tall or really wide.
它不希望变得更高或更宽
It wants to hug.
它希望 Hug
So, it has a high hugging priority.
所以它的 Hugging Priority 会很高
Other things, they might not care if they get bigger.
其他的元素，它们不在乎是否变得更大
Okay?
懂了吗？
Like this thing right here,
就像它
it really wants to hug vertically.
它总是希望在垂直方向 Hug
It doesn't mind if it gets stretched out horizontally.
它不在乎自己是否在横向被拉抻
All right?
懂了吗？
Okay.
好的
So, that's that.
就是这样
Now, let's go to, what are we going to do next here?
下一步应该做什么呢？
Let's add a couple more fields.
我们再添加几个 Text Field
That name, remember we had the name and the company?
还记得 name 和 company 吗？
Let's go add those and see what happens here.
把这些添加上去，看看会发生什么
So those are going to be text fields.
它们都是 Text Field
So they're labels rather, they're right here at the top.
它们是 Label，在顶部这里
So I'm just going to put these out here,
所以我们要把它们放在这里
grab a couple of these.
拽几个 Label
We'll make this one be name.
把这个改成 Name
We'll make this one be the company.
把这个改成 Company
All right, now where do I want these to be located?
我应该把它们放到哪里呢？
Well, I kind of want this to be right here.
我想把它放到这里
I really want it to be kind of like right here.
就是放在这里
Okay, not perfectly in the middle because I
不是放在最中间
am gonna put company right here.
因为我想把 Company 放在这里
So now it would be kind of offset down.
稍稍往下面偏移一点
But I guess I can say all right,
我觉得这还可以
I'll make these two things.
我可以处理好这两个
I'll have their horizontal spacing and
我会让它们 Horizontal Spacing
their Center Y's matched up.
并且把 Center Y 匹配起来
The centers vertically.
垂直部分的中央
It's kinda not exactly what I want, but it's close.
这可能有点不是我想要的，但是已经非常接近了
And then this guy, I will have his vertical spacing, and
对于这个 Label，我要让它 Vertical Spacing
his left edge lined up with the name.
并且 Left Edge 和 Name 连接起来
Right?
对吧？
That's pretty much what I want.
这大体上是我想要的
So that's not bad, but
还不错
really I don't want this lined up with the middle here.
但是我不想让它和中间排成一行
I want the bottom of this lined up with the middle.
我想让它的底部和中间排成一行
So how can I do that?
我怎么才能做到呢？
Okay, pay attention now.
现在集中注意力
It's very important to understand, because now
理解这部分很重要
we're gonna start looking at how these constraints work.
因为我们要开始看看这些 Constraint 是怎么工作的
So I'm gonna click on this constraint,
我先点击这个 Constraint
which causes me to inspect it here in the Inspector.
在 Inspector 中，我就可以对其进行检查
Okay? This is
OK?
what a constraint looks like.
这就是一个 Constraint
Notice the constraint has two items, a first item and
注意看这里的 Constraint 有两个 item
a second item.
First Item 和 Second Item
And, for each item, it says something about that item,
对于每一个 Item，都有一些关于 Item 的信息
like its center, or its bottom, or its top.
例如它的中间，底部或者顶部
Okay? If it had text,
如果上面有文字
it could be base lines.
Baseline 也可以选择
All right?
懂了吗？
So, each of them has something like that.
每一个都有类似的东西
And then, it has a relationship between them,
然后，它还有一个两个 Item 之间的关系
which could be equal, less than or
这个关系可是相等，小于或等于
equal, or greater than or equal.
大于或等于
So right now I have the center of this Stanford thing
现在，我使得 Standford 图标的中间和
equal to the center of the name thing.
Name 的中间相等
But it's perfectly fine for me to say I want the center of
对于我来说
the Stanford thing to match the bottom of the name thing.
把这个图标的中间和 Name 的底部对齐也是可以的
Okay?
OK？
Understand that?
懂了吗？
And then, down here you have this constant.
在这里，有一个 Constant
Okay?
OK？
The constants, there's two constants.
这里有两个常数
One is a multiplier, and one is a constant.
一个是 Multiplier 一个是 Constant
Okay?
OK?
So the constant is always added onto the end,
Constant 总是加在最后
and the multiplier is going to multiply the things that
Multiplier 的作用是
are being compared.
把比较的地方相乘
So it really doesn't make sense too much to multiply.
其实相乘没什么意义
But it kind of does.
但是也有点意义
Watch if I do four to one ratio.
我在这里填入 4:1
It's putting this bottom of this
它把它底部的设置成了
the ratio of four to one of the size of here.
这里大小的四倍
Okay? And
OK?
this can also be like, 0.5.
这里也可以填 0.5
Okay.
好的
Which is really tiny, so tiny that it's one.
0.5 有点小
Let's say two.
试试2
All right? So these can be numbers, or
这里可以填数字
they can be ratios.
也可以填比率
And then the constant is an amount added to it, like 50.
Constant 是增加的数量，例如50
Okay, so I've just added fixed 50 pixels.
在这里添加了50个像素
So it's just always added.
它总是在原有的基础上添加
So constant is always added, multiplier is multiplied.
Constant 总是添加，Multiplier 就是相乘
All constraints are this way, every single one.
每一个 Constraint 都是这样的
Okay? And,
OK?
some make sense with center or top bottom.
有一些对于 Center Top Bottom 有意义
Some of them make sense with width and height.
而有一些是 Width 和 Height 有意义
And when we do one in code,
当我们在代码里实现 Constraint 的时候
you're gonna see we're gonna do width and height.
你会看到，我们会处理 Width 和 Height
You know, but they're still in the same form.
但是它们的形式都是相同的
They always have the same form.
他们总是有相同的形式
That's why there's only one constructor for
这就是为什么在代码中
these layout constraint in the code.
这个 Layout Constraint 只有一个 Constructor（构造器）
Okay, and it just takes all of these things.
它把所有这些当做参数
The constant, the multiplier the first item.
Constant，Multiplier，First Item
Which thing on the first item?
哪个元素是 First Item
The relationship.
Relationship
And the second item, the second, and
Second Item
the thing on that, okay?
和 Second Item 上面的元素
So we're gonna see that.
我们以后会看到的
So, lets see if this worked.
看看我们所做的有没有效果
Just for fun let's go ahead and go back to our code, and
回到代码里
why are these things up.
把这些东西连接起来
Okay, so Ctrl+Drag.
按住 Ctrl 拖动鼠标
That's alright, from the name.
从 Name
oops, Undo, okay.
搞错了
Ctrl+Drag from the name.
从 Name
That is our Name Label and we'll go and
起名为 nameLabel
Ctrl+Drag from the company here.
同样方法
That is our Company Label.
把 Company 设置好
All right.
好的
And in our Update UI,
在 UpdateUI 里面
sorry about the width here, let's do this.
这有点挡住了，把它收回去点
In our Update UI here, we are going to update those.
在 UpdateUI 里面，我们来更新这两个 Label
So we'll just say that our Name Label that text,
把 nameLabel 的 text
equals our logged in user.
设置为 loggedInUser?
And if our logged in user is nil,
如果 loggedInUser 是 nil
then we'll just set the text to be nil as well.
把 text 设置为 nil 就可以了
So I'm using optional chaining there.
所以在这里我使用了可选链
But that's the name of the person.
这就是登陆者的名字
And then, our company label's text equals the logged in
然后，Company Label 的 text
user's company.
等于 loggedInUser?.company
Okay? Let's also set
OK?
that image view right there.
在这里也把 imageView 给设置好
Okay?
OK?
So we'll Ctrl+Drag from the image view
按住 Ctrl 拖动 imageView
that's just like any other thing.
就像之前做的一样
I can Ctrl+Drag this thing over, so let's do that.
我可以拖动它
I'm gonna call it the Image View.
把它起名为 imageView
Okay. And
OK.
we'll set that as well in our Update UI.
我们也要在 UpdateUI 里更新它
Here by saying imageview.image equals the logged in
把这里的 imageView.image 设置为
user's image.
登陆用户的 image
Unfortunately, this is not gonna work.
但是，这不会起作用
And why is this not gonna work?
它为什么不起作用呢？
Because Image is not defined in User.
因为 User 中没有定义 image
If we go look at User.
如果我们查看一下 User 类
Okay, user can't have an image because it's a model.
User 不能拥有 image，因为它是 model
It doesn't have any UI kit.
它没有导入 UIKit
There's no UI.
这里没有 UI
And UI image is a UI thing.
UIImage 是一个 UI 元素
Okay.
OK.
So we can't even model.
所以 model 里不能有它
But that doesn't stop us from having an image
但是这也不能组织我们拥有 image 这个 property
property MUser, because we can use extensions.
因为我们可以使用 extension
Okay.
OK
So here I'm gonna make an extension to User.
所以这里，我给 User 添加一个 extension
Okay, it's gonna be a var called image.
一个叫 image 的变量
It's gonna be a UIImage, UIImage, but I'm adding this
类型是 UIImage
in my controller so that's fine because, it's extending
我把它放到 controller 里
my model but it's not actually touching my model.
它扩展了我的 model，但是没有接触我的 model
My model is still purely fine.
model 还是没问题的
And to do this, I'm just gonna return basically a UIImage,
为了实现功能，在这里返回一个 UIImage
that is named the user's login.
name 是 User 中的 login
Now notice, I can refer to login here because this
看到了吗，我可以获取到 login
is user.
因为我们在 User 类中
This is on user, so
这是对 User 的扩展
login is a user thing, so I can refer to that, 'kay.
所以我可以获取到
But this is saying no, because this might return nil.
但是这有一个错误，因为它也许会返回 nil
So I'm gonna say.
我会说
If I can get let the image equal that,.
如果我能获取到 image
Then, I will return it.
我就返回它
Otherwise, I will return a UI image of some unknown user.
否则我就返回一个未知用户的 UIImage
I have. A thing there I
在这里
put in there called, unknown user.
我输入 unknown_user
That's just an image that I put there.
这是一张图片的名字
And this, I'm gonna make this optional so
我把它变成 optional
the whole thing can return optional.
所以内部就可以返回 optional
Okay?
OK?
So now, this is implemented.
现在，这个已经实现完毕了
This might return nill but
这个也许会返回 nil
that's okay, because this is allowed to be nill.
但是这也没问题，因为这个允许是 nil 的
And all is well.
万事俱备
So let's go take a look,
我们运行程序来看一下
now we should have our full UI functioning here.
所有 UI 的功能都已经实现了
Let's go on our iPhone here.
用 iPhone 运行一下
Oh, I know, right here,
哦，我知道了
okay, run, okay, here it is, so let's log in as madbum.
运行一下，我们用 madbum 登陆
And log in, and there we go.
登陆完毕
Oh, that looks terrible.
这看起来太糟糕了
What's going on here?
到底发生了什么？
Look at how it stretched this thing out, okay?
这个东西被拉抻开了
I want this hugging.
我希望它是 Hug 的
I don't like this.
我不希望这样
This is not hugging, okay?
它没有 Hug
But there's another problem too,
这里也有个问题
we'll look at this in a second.
我们稍后再看
But let's look at it this way, though.
我们旋转一下屏幕
Same thing, it's no good.
同样地，效果很不好
Okay? So, we're getting close.
不过已经很接近了
Why is this happening?
为什么会这样呢？
Well, the reason that this is happening is because we have
发生这件事的原因是
all these things attached to each other, and, so
我们把这些 view 都相互依附在一起
we can fix this in two ways, actually.
其实我们可以通过两种方式修复
One way is I can go here, and change this guy,
一种是，去到这里，改变它
who's hugging priority can just be less so
把它的 Hugging Priority 调低
that these guys will be more likely to hug.
所以其他这些就更可能 Hug
Okay.
OK.
Down on their text.
在它们的 text 下面
So I'm gonna set this guy's vertical hugging priority
所以我要设置它的 Vertical Hugging Priority
down to let's say 200.
把它调到 200
The rest of these are at say, 250.
剩下的这些还是 250
Okay, these are all at 250.
它们都是 250
I'm gonna set mine down to 200.
我把它调低到 200
Okay.
好的。
So we run, let's log in as mad mom again.
我们再次以madbum登陆。
There we go, okay, so it didn't squish this,
走起，很好，这个没被压扁了，
although wow, now it's stretched this thing way up.
但是，下面的图片被拉伸了。
I don't really like that either.
我不希望这样。
Okay?
明白吗？
So why is that happening?
那这是为什么呢?
Well that's happening because of this constraint right here.
这是因为这个约束。
This constraint says,
这个约束说，
that the distance from the top of the image to the bottom of
从图片顶部到登陆按钮底部的距离
here has to equal.
必须相等于。
The standard value equal.
标准值。
I don't want equal.
但我不想等于一个确定的值。
I'm gonna say, if it's greater than or equal, that's fine.
我只需要，大于或等于就可以了。
Okay? So this is where you
明白吗？这种情况下
would use a greater than or equals, because this spacing,
就可以用到大于或等于选项，因为这个距离，
I just want to make sure it doesn't smash into it.
我只需要确保图片不和按钮重叠就行。
But if it's smaller, that's okay.
所以图片小一点也是没问题的。
I don't mind that.
我并不在意。
All right. So now, let's try madbum.
好的，我们再次登陆。
Madbum.
输入madbum
Okay, perfect, so now it's doing that, and
很好，完美解决，看这里，而且
over here, oops, over this way, working fine.
在横屏模式下，同样没问题。
Okay?
看到没？
So we're getting good,
事情很顺利，
there's only really two things left that are problems in
整个程序就只剩下
this whole thing,
两个问题了，
one is this guy getting smashed off, gotta fix that.
一个是这两个文本的内容没有显示完整，我们来修复它。
And we fix that.
来解决这个问题。
You already know how to fix that.
你应该知道如何解决这个问题了
I'm just gonna take this, and make it so
只需要选中它，然后
that this thing hooks to this edge.
和父视图的边界关联起来。
And same thing with this thing hooking to this guy's edge.
这个标签也是一样。
And again, I don't want them to be anything but
同样，我需要把他们的值设置为
a standard value here.
标准值。
So I'm gonna have this one be zero.
选这个或者0.
And same thing with this one right here.
这个也是一样。
I don't like this.
我不想要这个。
Nonstandard values.
非标准值。
In fact, I've got a couple of them
事实上，前面还有很多
left over from previous things here, so let's fix these.
这样的问题需要修复。
Standard Values.
标准值。
Okay?
明白吗？
All right.
好的。
Everything look good there?
现在看起来都正常了。
No magic numbers?
没有 magic numbers吧？
Oh, here's the magic number.
oh， 这里还有一个。
Let's get rid of that.
改掉它。
Standard Value.
标准值。
That it, okay, got all those.
好的，全部修改了。
Everything looks fine, it moved.
看起来很不错。
So now, we should be all fixed and ready to go.
现在，应该都修改正确了，可以测试了。
Alright, madbum again.
好的，再次登录。
Secure this time, don't want you to know madbum's password.
换成安全状态，不想让你看到密码。
Okay, looking good, oh, still didn't quite work.
好的，看起来很好，但是，好像还是有问题。
We got the name but why did this thing.
姓名标签很正常，但是下面这个。
Not do that.
不对。
What's going on there?
这是怎么回事？
Same circle Giants got put up.
同样的问题有发生了。
The reason there is this guy's hogging priority is too
原因是这个标签的hugging 优先级别太
low, okay.
低了。
I'm sorry, his compression resistance, I mean,
很抱歉，是compression resistance值才对，
is too low.
太低了。
He's allowing himself to be compressed.
它允许自己被挤压。
Okay.
好的。
So here, we need to have the horizontal compression
这里，我们需要提高它的水平
resistance of this guy be higher.
resistance值。
So I'm gonna set it to 800.
就设置为800.
Doesn't really matter what we set,
具体设置成多大并不是很重要，
as long as it's higher than.
只要大于
The other things, like this one, which is 750, so
其他视图的值，比如这个，它是750，
let's set this guy's also, oops, it's compression to 800.
把这个也设置为800.
Okay, so that prevents them from being compressed down so
这样一来，就可以避免他们被挤压
that their text won't show.
而无法完整显示文本了。
Okay.
好的。
Oh, well, that's not so good.
oh，情况不妙。
Okay, so we fixed one problem, we introduces another one.
看，我们解决了一个问题，又来了另一个。
So we certainly-
所以实际上
There are two problems with this,
这里有两个问题，
actually, number one, this is not the right aspect ratio.
首先，图片的宽高比例不对。
This is not what the Giants logo looks like,
Giants logo可不是这样的，
you can barely even tell it's the Giants.
你甚至都认不出来。
And number two is, it's way too small, okay?
问题二，太小了，不是吗？
Look at all this empty space I've got up here, okay, so
看上面的空白空间。
we've got two things to fix here.
所以还有两个问题解决后
And then we're done.
就完成了。
One is make this aspect ratio be enforced, and
一个是修正图片的宽高比问题，
another one is put this in the right space.
另一个是将它放到正确的位置。
In this size class which is I got a lot of vertical space.
在这个size class 我们有充足的垂直空间。
So, lets go ahead and fix the aspect ratio one first.
我们先修复图宽高比的问题。
You know that one.
你可能会想。
We'd like to be able to just go here and
我们可以到这里
add some kind of constraint, but we can't actually do that.
加一些约束就好了，但事实上，不可以。
And that's because if you remember, when we look
因为，不知道你是否记得
at a constraint, its constant and multiplier are constants.
一个约束的的constant和multiplier值是常量。
And every time we get a new image,
每次图片更新的时候，
it has a different aspect ratio.
它的宽高比不同。
Okay?
明白吗？
So, unless we wanted to force everyone's image to
除非我们限制每个图片
be the same aspect ratio, we need code to
的宽高比相同，不然的话，我们需要
do this because we have to calculate that aspect ratio.
在代码中来计算这个宽高比才行。
So, this is what that looks like.
所以，仔细看好了。
I'm gonna go through this pretty fast because
我会以非常快的速度演示因为
we're over time already, so you can watch it here.
时间不多了，看这里。
So, I'm gonna do this like this.
我会这样做。
I'm gonna create a new var,
新建一个变量，
which is an aspectRatioConstraint(), and
命名为aspectRatioConstraint
it's going to be of type NSLayoutConstraint.
类型为NSLayoutConstraint
This is the type of those constraints.
这是所有约束的类型。
All those constraints in there it is of this type, okay.
所有的约束都是这个类型，是的。
Now, I'm gonna create another var called image, UIImage.
现在创建另一个变量，叫做image
And it can be optional, it's fine.
可以为空，所以设置为optional类型。
And it's just gonna be a computed property,
这将使一个computed property，
where I'm gonna get and set my image views properties.
我会在其中设置和获取我的image view视图。
So I'm really just gonna return imageView.image,
我只需要返回 imageView.image,
I'm gonna set her.
设置她。
I'm just going to set it.
设置好就可以了。
Let's go to wide here.
这边加宽一点。
Wide mode.
更宽一点。
Okay, in the center,
好的，在setter方法里面，
I'm just gonna set it imageView.image = image.
我只需要设置imageView.image = image.
Now, why am I creating this little computer property?
那么，我为什么创建这个computed property？
Because every time I set my imageView's image I
因为每当我设置imageView的image的时候
want to update this aspect ration constraint, okay.
我需要更新图片的宽高比例约束，明白？
So, if I can let this constrained view,
所以，如果imageView不为空
this is the view I'm trying to constrain,
就是我想添加约束的视图，
which is the image view.
也就是imageView。
If I can let it equal something.
如果我可以let出来。
In other words it's not nill, okay?
换句话说就是不为nil，明白吗？
And if I can let the new image equal new value,
然后如果newValue不为空，
because this is, we're setting an image here, so
就是我们设置的新图片，
if I'm able to set an image in this constraint, screen view.
我们就可以为他添加约束了。
Then I'm gonna create this
这样我只需要让
aspectRatioConstraint equal to something.
aspectRatioConstraint等于某个值就可以了。
If I can't set the new image, then I'm gonna
如果image为空，
set the aspectRatioContraint equal to nil, 'kay.
我会讲aspectRatioConstraint设置为nil，明白吗？
So someone set my image to nil.
如果别人将图片设置为nil。
I can't have a constraint.
我就无法添加约束了。
The aspect ration of nil image is nothing, so I don't,
空图片并没有宽高比，所以不必，
can't even have a constraint there.
设置约束。
So how do I create this constraint in the case I
当我们获取到图片的时候
do have an image for imageView?
怎样创建这个约束呢？
I just do it with a constructor,
只需要调用构造器即可，
NSLayoutConstraint, okay?
NSLayoutConstraint（），明白吗？
Here's what NSLayoutConstraint's
NSLayoutConstraint（）构造器
constructor looks like.
就是这样子的。
It's got all these things here,
它需要很多参数，
let's go through them one at a time, and
我们一个一个来，
it looks just like that inspector I showed you.
就像inspector一样。
So one is the thing we're trying to constrain.
首先是你需要添加约束的视图。
Which is our image view, what attribute of that, it's width,
也就是imageView，被约束的属性是width，
how do we want to relate it to our constants and multipliers?
和constants和multipliers的关系是怎样的呢？
Well, we're going to do aspect ratio, so
我们想做宽高比约束，所以
we want the width multiplied times the height.
我们需要width=height*x
So the width is going to equal the height times the aspect
所以我们让 宽 等于 高 乘以 宽高比
ratio, so this is going to be equal.
所以我们选择等号。
And what are we relating it to?
然后相对于哪个视图呢？
We could relate it to another thing, but
我们可以选择其他视图，但是
this is the imageviews own aspect ratio, so it's relating
这里是imageView自己的宽高比，所以相对于
it to itself, okay, and what attribute is it relating to?
它自己，好，那相对于哪个属性呢？
It's height, and what is the multiplier going to be?
是height，那么乘以哪个数呢？
It's going to be that new image aspect ratio.
乘以图片的aspectRatio属性。
Okay? And then this constant gets
明白吗？然后是增加的常量
added in.
数值。
We don't want to add anything else in.
我们不需要增加多余的值。
We just want to multiply.
我们只需要乘以宽高比就可以了。
So here I'm making this image view's width equal to it's
所以我们让宽等于高乘以
height times this multiplier.
乘以宽高比即可。
Make sense?
明白吗？
That's the constraint I'm putting on it.
这是我天津的约束。
That's how constraints work.
约束就是这样工作的。
That's all it is.
就是这些。
Now a couple of things are not good here.
现在还有一些问题。
One is there is no such method aspect ratio on UI image.
一个是，UIImage没有aspectRatio方法。
So I'm gonna go down here and do an extension for that too.
所以我们到下面添加一个extension。
UIImage var aspectRatio.
添加一个aspectRatio熟悉。
It's gonna be a CGFloat.
CGFloat类型。
I'm just going to return if my size.height is not zero,
如果不为0就直接返回，
because I don't wanna have to divide by zero.
因为我不想除数为0.
Then I'm going to return size.width divided by
然后返回宽除以高，
size.height, otherwise I guess I'll just return zero.
如果为0救直接返回。
Okay, so I just added this var to UI image,
好的，为UIImage添加了这个属性，
because I wanted it and
因为我需要它而且
it makes my code read really nicely right here, okay?
这让代码非常可读又美观，不是吗？
Perfectly reasonable.
非常完美。
And the only other thing is, when I set this aspect ratio
最后一个问题是，当我设置这个宽高比约束时
constraint I'm creating it, but now I need to enforce it.
我需要将它添加到图片上并使之生效。
So how do you enforce a constraint?
那么怎样使一个约束生效呢？
If you have one in your hand, how do you force it?
如果你现在有一个约束，怎样使他生效？
And it's very simple,
非常简单，
you just add it as a constraint to the view.
你只需要将它添加到视图就可以了。
So I'm in my view controller here, so
我现在在控制器中，
I'm going to add this constraint to my view.
我将在这里为视图添加约束。
So in didSet, any time this aspect ratio gets set up here,
在didSet方法中，每次设置aspetRatio的时候，
this is where I set it.
我就在这里设置它。
Either to nil or this.
要么为空或不为空。
Then if I can let this new
如果这个约束
constraint equal the aspect ratio of constraint.
我可以let出来。
In other words, if its not nil.
换句话说，如果不为空。
Then I'm gonna tell my view please add this constraint.
我就让视图添加这个约束。
Now I also, by the way, when it set I want to
同样，随便的，在willSet中
remove any old constraint cause I might already have
我们需要移除掉
put a constraint from the previous image I was showing.
已经存在的约束。
So I'm gonna say if let the existing constraint
所以如果aspectRatioConstant
equal the aspect ratio constraint and
不为空而且
this is my will set so this hasn't been set yet.
由于这是willSet方法，所以这时aspectRatioConstrain还没有设置
Then I'm gonna say remove the constraint.
我只需要移除已存在的约束即可。
Make sense? So that's it.
明白吗？就是这样。
Okay, and that's all we need to do.
这是我们所有需要做的。
So let's go ahead and run here.
让我们来测试一下。
So I'm going to go back to this view here,
更换一下视图模式，
and select Storyboard here.
选择storyboard。
All right, so we're going to run this.
开始运行。
I haven't changed the storyboard since last we
我们至始至终都没有更改过storyboard，
talked, but now when we go madbomb here.
我们直接运行看看。
This thing, it didn't work.
好像没有成功。
So why does this not work?
这是为什么呢？
because, sorry about this, forgot something.
因为，很抱歉，忘了设置些东西。
When I set my image, I'm not calling my new image property.
当我设置imageView视图的时候，我没有调用这个新image属性。
I put all that nice code here inside this image
我把实现都写在了image属性的
property, right?
的监听方法中，记得吗？
Right here.
就是这里。
But I didn't call it.
但是，我忘了使用它。
So here I'm actually calling that, so sorry about that.
所以，现在我们改成image，很抱歉。
Why did I [INAUDIBLE] there, imageView.image equals
这里好像写错了，imageView.image应该等于
newValue, sorry about that, newValue.
newValue，很抱歉。
Let's go back here, all right.
再运行一次看看。
See, when I rush, then I make mistakes like that.
你看，当我写的太匆忙，就会出些错误。
Okay, all right!
好的！
Whoo.
Whoo。
I think that's the Giants logo down there.
这下面应该就是Giants logo了。
At least it's the right aspect ratio.
至少宽高比是正确的。
But clearly, it's terrible to have that thing there
但是很显然，把它放在这里很糟糕
because it's too tiny and we got all this space.
因为太小了，而上面却有这么大空间空着。
So last thing we're going to do is
所以，最后一步操作需要
use the size classes to put this thing up here, okay?
使用size class把logo放到上面来，明白吗？
How do we do that?
那要怎样做呢？
We go back to our storyboard right here.
我们回到storyboard。
And right now, we've been doing all our
现在为止，我们都是用的
work in this any any.
any any来布局。
Okay, and what we want to do is when we're regular height,
我们只需要，在regular高度的时候，
we're gonna put the name and the company underneath.
将name和company标签放在底部。
So I'm gonna go here to where it says any width,
所以我需要到这里改成any 宽度，
regular height.
regular高度。
You see where it says along the top, any width,
你看到了吗？可以在上面改成any宽度，
regular height.
regular高度。
See that?
看到了吗？
I'm gonna click there.
我点击这里。
Now I'm editing.
开始编辑。
You see the bar at the bottom is bright blue.
你看底部有一个蓝色的条目。
That's to remind you,
这是用来提醒你，
oh hey, you are editing a specific size class here.
嘿，你现在是在一个特定的size class下编辑。
But we're editing any width, regular height.
因为我们现在在any 宽度和register高度下编辑。
And so here, this should be in red if I
如果我现在移动他们，
was doing a slide, this would be in red, which is
约束会变成红色，也就是说
when you go to another size class, and you're going to be
当你在一个的新size class下编辑的时候，如果你打算
moving things around, remove the constraints on
移动视图，先去除你要移动的视图上的约束
the things you're going to be moving before you move them.
再进行移动，
Because once you start moving them,
因为一旦你开始移动视图，
it's going to be hard to remember, what did that go to.
你就很难记住这些约束了。
So here I am selecting these all and
所以我选中这几个视图然后
I am going to go over here and remove the constraint,
到这里移除约束，
clear the constraints, only from the selected views,
选择清除约束，只清除选中视图的约束，
these three things I have selected.
也就是我选中的这三个视图。
So we're going to clear those constraints,
我们会清除他们所有的约束，
now they have no constraints,
现在他们身上没有约束了，
now I am just going to move them around to where I want.
我可以随便移动了。
So I want that one there,
我把这个放这里，
I want these down here at the bottom.
这个放在底部。
Put that in the corner.
放在角落。
I'll put that on top of there.
然后把这个放在上面。
We'll put this down here like that.
放下一点。
Now we'll put the new constraints, so
现在我们加新的约束，这样
now all new constraints that I'm making are only for
所有新加的约束
this size class.
只对当前size class有效。
Okay? Not for any-any anymore.
明白吗？不再对any-any有效。
I'm kind of forked off here.
就像叉掉了一样。
So let's put some new constraints on here.
现在我会加新的约束。
This one is leaving space.
这个leading space。
This one is leading space.
This one is bottom space.
这个bottom space。
We want these separated.
这两个需要分开。
Vertical space.
vertical space。
We want these two separated.
我们需要这两个也分开。
We want this one over here leading space.
这个也添加leading space。
We want this to go all the way across, and
这一个横向延伸到边缘，然后
then go trailing space.
加上trailing space。
You also want this one to go all the way across, and
这样也占满宽度，然后
trailing space.
trailing space。
Okay.
好的。
Again, we would probably go here.
同样，我们需要到这里。
Let's see what we've got here.
好像有警告。
Frames are different, that's good.
Frames不同，这很简单。
Let's go ahead and update our frames.
更新frame就可以了。
Okay, looks good.
好的，看起来不错。
All looks good.
都很好。
Again, we would probably get rid of these magic numbers
再次强调，我们肯能需要去除所有magic numbers
like this.
像这个。
We don't like that.
我们不需要它。
We get rid of that.
去掉。
We did this one.
这个改了。
We don't like that.
也不需要这个。
We go select on this guy.
选择这个视图。
We've got this here, that.
这个也需要更改。
Same thing this one.
这个也是。
Okay, he got none, so we're good.
好的，修改完毕。
We're good to go.
可以测试了。
So now we've created this size class.
现在我们创建了这个size class。
One has different arrangement of views and
它有着不同的布局和
different constraints.
不同的约束。
So now when we run.
我们运行看看。
We'll see here.
马上就看到效果了。
Hit mad bum again.
登陆。
There it is.
就是这样。
It's using this space much more
现在更充分地利用了
effectively keeping this in it's normal aspect ratio, but
垂直方向上的空间，同时保证宽高比正确，并且
in this way it goes back to the old way.
在横屏模式下以原来的方式布局。
The any, any way, right?
也就是any any 记得吗？
Okay, and this is true if we go to someone else.
好的，我们用另一个账户登陆试试。
Hennessy.
Hennessy。
There, okay, see how that keeps the same aspect ratio
看，宽高比正常
and uses that space?
而且充分利用水平空间。
Really uses the space nicely here, no.
真的充分利用了空间，不。
>> [LAUGH]
laugh
>> Now why did that happen, okay?
这是为什么呢？
Because when I cleared the constraints here,
因为当我清除约束的时候，
okay, to make this new space, I also cleared this little
增加控件的同时，我也清除了
constraint that went up here, this vertical spacing.
上面这个约束，垂直距离约束。
Right?
明白吗？
This vertical spacing here wants to be the greater than
垂直距离需要大于
or equal to, and standard value.
或等于标准值。
Okay? So sometimes when you
明白吗？有时候当你
go to another size class, you delete the constraints,
切换到新的size class，你删除约束，
you move things around, oh, you still have
然后移动视图，你仍然需要
to basically debug the new one just as much as the old one.
做一些调试来保证之前的约束有效。
So here now,
好，再运行看看。
let's go see if our illustrious leader's log in.
登陆看是否显示正确。
It's good and it is.
很好，显示正常。
Okay?
看到了吗？
All right.
好的。
Sorry to take so long.
很抱歉拖堂这么久。
Thank you.
非常感谢。
I'll be here if you have any questions,
如果有问题可以提问，
otherwise I'll see you on Wednesday.
没有的话我们星期三见。
>> For more, please visit us at Stanford.edu.
更多内容，请访问Stanford.edu.